对你而言  选择萨拉·佩林是考虑赢得选举
For you, picking Sarah Palin was about winning an election,
而不是考虑副总统的最佳人选
not necessarily about who's gonna be best as vice president.
我的职责是提出政治建议
My job is to give political advice.
斯蒂夫·施密特
高级竞选顾问
为了赢得选举  需要兵行险招
We needed to do something bold to try to win the race.
如果能重新来过
If you had it to do over again,
你还会挑选她作为竞选搭档吗
would you have her on the ticket?
本字幕由YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
■
翻译：某豚 allen0314 愤怒的小榴莲 柠檬meg 亲爱的小饭
2007年八月
翻译：原小如 elflife ztonyy 校对：cheeseflower 笨熊猫
■
加州  萨克拉门托
-你好  -他们恨我  斯蒂夫
- Hello. - They fuckin' hate me, Steve.
谁恨你
Who's that, sir?
都是保守派的媒体评论员
林博  汉尼提  科尔特
Limbaugh, Hannity, Coulter.
他们都在拿我开涮  跟狂欢似的
They're dancing on my grave like it's fucking Mardi Gras.
有可能  但倒数也有好处
That may be true, but there's an upside to being in last place.
你能畅所欲言
You can say what you truly feel.
-你觉得我畏畏缩缩吗  -是的  参议员
- You think I've been holding back - I do, Senator.
增兵计划[指对伊拉克]确实有效
The surge is working,
但其他人都不敢这么说
but no one else is brave enough to say it.
都是共和党初选的竞争对手
罗姆尼  朱利安尼  赫卡比
Romney, Giuliani, Huckabee--
你所有的对手都避而不谈
all your opponents are hedging.
甚至你在上次辩论中都有所犹豫
Even you hesitated at the last debate.
有个伟大的人曾经告诉我说
A great man once told me,
"宁愿输掉竞选  也不愿国家战败"
"I would rather lose the election than see the country lose this war."
我不是在说空话  斯蒂夫
And I meant it, Steve.
那就说出来吧  先生
Then say it, sir.
约翰·麦凯恩不说中听的话  只说真话
John McCain doesn't say what's popular, he says what's right.
我建议你  找些曾经的战俘同胞
My advice would be to get some old pow buddies together
开大篷车全国巡讲
and travel the country in a small caravan.
住劣等旅馆  去退伍军协做演讲
Stay in shitty hotels, do American legion halls,
去海外退伍军人站演讲
V.F.W. Posts,
陪老兵喝喝酒  顺便享受生活
have a few beers and enjoy yourself.
还真他妈该这样
You're right, God damn it.
我不知道我到底怎么了
I don't know what the hell's wrong with me.
太沉迷于赢得提名  而迷失了自己
You get so caught up in winning, you start to lose yourself.
其实不难
It's gonna be easy
你只要传达一个信息就好了
because there's only one message you need to get across.
是吗  什么信息
Yeah? What's that?
约翰·麦凯恩以国家为先
John McCain puts country first.
考虑过加入我们吗
Would you consider joining us?
哪怕只是几周
Even just for a few weeks?
参议员  竞选人之中  我最仰慕你
Senator, there is no one in this race I admire more than you,
但我答应我妻子了  不趟这趟浑水
but I promised my wife that I would sit this cycle out.
我知道  斯蒂夫
I know that, Steve,
好歹考虑一下吧
but will you just think about it?
考虑下  好吗
Just do that-- just think about it, will you?
我考虑下吧  参议员
Of course, Senator.
-你保证  -我会的  我保证
- You promise? - I will, I promise.
好  我明天再联系你
Great, I'll call you tomorrow.
-没问题  -谢了  斯蒂夫
- Okay. - Thanks, Stevie boy.
糟糕
Fuck.
麦凯恩参议员今日重组其核心竞选团队
Senator McCain today re-shuffling his most senior campaign staff.
约翰·麦凯恩赢得了新罕布什尔州初选
John McCain wins the New Hampshire primary,
来自亚利桑那的参议员  上演绝地反击
a huge comeback for the Senator from Arizona.
你都能听见他们在我背后喊口号
You hear them chanting behind me--
"老麦回归了  老麦回归了"
"Mac is back, Mac is back."
约翰·麦凯恩在南卡罗来纳州大获全胜
A big win for John McCain in South Carolina,
这是一场他渴求已久的胜利
a win that he will relish.
第二次竞选总统的他  这次能赢吗
The question on the campaign trail was can a souffle rise twice?
约翰·麦凯恩赢得了共和党总统候选人提名
John McCain wins the Republican presidential nomination.
这是见证历史的一夜
What a historic night.
他们曾说  我们死定了
And they said we were dead.
下一站  进军白宫
Next Stop, the White House.
规则改变
奥巴马  奥巴马
Obama! Obama!
谢谢
Thank you.
2008年7月24日奥巴马柏林演讲
柏林人民  世界人民
People of Berlin and people of the world,
我们面临的挑战很严峻
the scale of our challenge is great.
前路漫漫
The road ahead will be long.
但我要说
But I come before you to say that
我们有为自由而战的传统
we are heirs to a struggle for freedom.
我们的民族  充满希望
We are a people of improbable hope
放眼未来  心怀坚定
with an eye towards the future, with resolve in our heart.
让我们铭记这一历史  书写自己的命运
Let us remember this history and answer our destiny
2008年7月24日
重塑世界
and remake the world once again.
感谢柏林人民  上帝保佑  谢谢
Thank you, Berlin. God bless you. Thank you.
他要在救活一个婴儿  我们就真完了
If he heals a sick baby, we're really fucked.
竞选经理
里克·戴维斯
我们落后15个百分点
We're down by 15.
如果他的大会演说也那么好
If his convention speech is as good as that--
会比这更好
it'll be better.
那党代会时  我们就落后20个百分点了
Then we'll be trailing by 20 going into St. Paul.
共和党全国代表大会在圣保罗举行
马克·萨尔特
高级顾问
讲稿撰写人
斗争很艰苦  约翰
It's an uphill battle, John.
毛主席曾说过
Well, as Chairman Mao was fond of saying,
麦凯恩最爱引用的语录
最黑暗的时刻过后  便是彻底黑暗
"It's always darkest before it's completely black."
参议员  你不要引用毛主席  我很担心
Senator, it always concerns me when you quote Chairman Mao.
这家伙筹集资金的能力  堪比人肉取款机
This guy is raising money like he's some sort of a human ATM machine.
约翰  如果需要
John, if there ever was a time
播放瑞特牧师的广告  就是此时了
to run a reverend Wright ad, this is that time.
奥巴马家庭牧师  言辞偏激
-绝对不行  -同意
- Absolutely not. - I agree.
有人拍到  他的牧师说"天煞美国"
There's footage of his own reverend saying "God damn America."
这是我们手里唯一的强力武器了
It's the single best weapon we've got.
我的竞选  要让我的孩子们自豪
I want to run a fucking campaign that my kids can be proud of,
所以不可以攻击一个黑人牧师
and that precludes attacking a black reverend.
我觉得我们整个思路都错了
I think we're going about this all wrong.
这个人上了各大新闻杂志的封面
This man is on the cover of every news magazine.
甚至娱乐杂志的封面
He's on the cover of every entertainment magazine.
柏林二十万人为他尖叫
He's got 200,000 people screaming for him in Berlin.
他又做了些什么呢
And what has he done?
一个毫无建树的人
A man of no accomplishment
成为了世界上最知名的人物
has become the biggest celebrity in the world,
我们一直在追赶他  想打败他
and we keep trying to reach up and pull him down.
我们只需向国民提一个非常简单的问题
What we need to do is ask the American people a very simple question:
你希望下任总统是一位政治家
Do you want a statesman to be your next president...
还是名人呢
Or do you want a celebrity?
可以试试看
Try it.
他是世界上最知名的人物
He's the biggest celebrity in the world.
奥巴马  奥巴马
Obama! Obama!
但作为领导人  他合适吗
But is he ready to lead?
油价飙升
With gas prices soaring,
奥巴马却反对近海钻探
Barack Obama says no to offshore drilling
反而声称要提升电力税
and says he'll raise taxes on electricity?
更高的税率  更多的石油进口
Higher taxes, more foreign oil--
这才是奥巴马的目的
that's the real Obama.
干得好  弗瑞德
Great job, Fred.
我还以为我们比他们成熟呢
I thought we were the grown-ups in this race.
约翰  那是他女朋友
John, it's his girlfriend.
这是警世寓言  约翰
This is a cautionary tale, John.
说真的
It's what I'm talking about.
是啊  那就...
Yeah, right. Yeah, let's--
-再看一遍  -别这样  拜托
- let's watch it again. - No, I can't, I can't! Please.
懂没  就是这意思
See, that's what I'm talking about.
这帮人真不可置信
Now can you believe these guys?
独立民主党人  却力挺麦凯恩竞选
他想要利伯曼做竞选搭档
He wants Lieberman on the ticket.
-那是自然  -那就悲剧了
- Of course he does. - Disaster.
也可能载入史册
Or historic.
-或者载入史册的悲剧  -约翰喜欢他
- Or historic disaster. - John loves him.
这可能是两党联合上的一大壮举
It would be a strong move towards bi-partisanship.
各位  基础选民已经在担心
Guys, the base is already concerned
约翰不是正宗的保守派
that John is not a true conservative.
我不觉得选一个支持堕胎的犹太裔民主党
Now, I don't think picking a pro-choice Jewish Democrat
还曾是阿尔·戈尔竞选伙伴
who just happened to be Al Gore's running mate
能减少这种疑虑
is going to alleviate that concern.
也许我们能让麦凯恩宣誓不连任
Maybe we have McCain make a one-term pledge.
他在某个大型演讲上宣布
He announces in some huge speech that
他和一名民主党人将联合执政一个任期
he and a Democrat are joining together for one term
以便让两党联合起来
so that the parties can come together
解决国家的重大问题
and solve this country's greatest problems.
也许  如果宣誓不连任的话
Maybe, with a one-term pledge.
没有比选乔·利伯曼更表明我们国家为先了
Nothing says country first like picking Joe Lieberman.
如果要奏效  就要绝对保密
Well, if it's gonna work, it has to remain absolutely secret,
一直到党代会才揭晓
right up until the convention.
要是泄漏了  右派会搞砸一切
If it gets leaked, the right will kill it.
约翰·麦凯恩决定在大会期间
John McCain's decision to put Joe Lieberman
将乔·利伯曼推上前台
front and center at his convention
让民主党和共和党都颇感不安
has the unique distinction of unsettling both Democrats and Republicans.
我认为  让他成为
I think the idea of him being
共和党的副总统候选人
the Republican vice presidential nominee
可能导致大会分裂
would split the convention.
作为内阁成员  没问题  但不能是副总统
In the cabinet, fine. Not as V.P.
糟糕的选择  保守派会疏离本党的
Bad choice. Conservatives will bolt.
麦凯恩和利伯曼的组合太怪异了
Comedy team of McCain and Lieberman.
也就玩玩大西洋城能有希望
Maybe they'll play Atlantic city this summer.
谢谢
Thank you.
出了什么事
So what the fuck happened?
林赛·格雷厄姆想给这个想法寻求支持
Lindsey Graham was trying to build support for the idea
-结果消息走漏了  -该死的  林赛
- and it leaked. - God damn it, Lindsey.
权当安慰吧
Well, if it's any consolation,
数据表明  如果你选择了利伯曼
my numbers show that if you pick Lieberman
或者任何支持堕胎的候选人
or any pro-choice candidate,
你40%的核心支持者都可能不再支持你
40%啊
无党派人士的支持几乎不会增加
And you gain very few independents.
总体来说  各方都不讨好
Overall, it's a wide-net negative.
我们打了很多电话  有些人觉得
We've made a lot of calls. Some people don't even think
利伯曼甚至不会通过大会的同意
Lieberman can make it through the convention.
其他人说  他能当上  但会撕裂党派
Others say, yeah, he can, but he's gonna rip the party in half.
但乔很完美  我们都是
But Joe is perfect. We're both mavericks
被党内混蛋痛恨的异端
that are hated by the assholes in our own parties.
联手能对国家产生巨大的正面作用
It could have a tremendous healing effect on the country.
没有基础选民的支持  我们没法获胜
We can't win without our base.
选利伯曼是治国良策  但不是获胜之道
Lieberman is the right thing to do, but the wrong way to win.
还审核过谁
Who all have we vetted?
罗姆尼  克里斯特  波仑蒂
Romney, Crist, Pawlenty.
-正在审核彭博  -谁能帮我们赢得竞选呢
- We're trying to vet Bloomberg. - Who can we win with?
-都不能  -都不能
- None of them. - None of them?
约翰  奥巴马改变了整个竞选基调
John, Obama just changed the entire dynamic.
时代不同了啊
It is a change year, sir.
我们急需改变规则的人选
We desperately need a game-changing pick,
这些中年白人男士可不是什么改变规则的人
and none of these middle-aged white guys are game-changers.
那...怎么办
So...what?
我就自认倒霉  甘愿输掉
I just fuck off and die?
数据显示  我们得做四件事
Well, the data shows we have four things we have to do.
赢回无党派人士的支持
We have to win back the independents,
激起基础选民的热情
we have to excite the base,
和布什政府拉开距离
we have to distance ourselves from the Bush administration,
还必须减少女性选民的支持率差距
and we have to close the gender gap.
差距有多大
How bad is the gap?
相当大
It's fatal.
你的男性支持率领先20个百分点  这很好
You've got a 20% advantage with men, which is great,
但女性支持率低了20个百分点
but a 20% deficit with women.
你得在女性选民支持率上提升15个百分点
You've got to pick up 15% with females.
如果在这块落后5个百分点以上
Because if you're trailing by more than five with them,
你就输了
you lose.
那就给我找个女人来
So find me a woman.
女士们  谁会中选呢
All right, ladies. Who's it gonna be?
梅格·惠特曼支持堕胎
Meg Whitman supports abortion rights.
支持堕胎  支持堕胎
Pro-choice, pro-choice.
-你是谁呢  -这组太阳能电池板
- Who are you? - These solar arrays combined
将为我们提供三千四百万瓦的电力
will allow us to produce 34 megawatts of power...
为保障风险管理成为我们保障...
To make sure that risk management is the best that we can do to secure...
众所周知  奥古斯塔没有收费公路
But as you know, the turnpike ends here in Augusta.
基于这点...
At that point...
她叫什么来着
What was her name?
一旦阿拉斯加获准 安全可靠地开发本土资源
Once Alaska is allowed to very responsibly and safely develop our resources,
将能降低全美的能源支出
we'll lower costs of energy across the United States,
由此能为国家提供
and then we'd be able to secure the nation
洁净的国内能源供应
with a clean, domestic supply of energy.
另外  从我个人的角度
And I say that, Charlie, even personally.
我的独子今年十八岁
My one and only son, my 18-year-old,
刚刚报名参了军
he just signed up for the United States Army.
现在正在新兵训练营
He's at boot camp right now.
我就想
And I'm thinkin', you know,
这孩子正竭尽全力
this kid is doing all that he can within his power
保卫国家的安全
to help secure and defend the United States.
每位民选官员都该扪心自问
Every elected official had better be asking themselves,
你们也能做到这样吗
are you doing as much also?
你们倾尽全力了吗
Are you doing all that you can?
她是个明星
She's a star.
她强烈反对堕胎  因此在四十四岁时
She's so passionately pro-life that at age 44,
她没有打掉一个
she decided to keep a child
怀孕中期被诊断出有唐氏综合症的孩子
that she knew mid-term had Down's Syndrome.
还有很多地方  基础选民会喜欢她
And there's a lot more that the base will love.
她在阿拉斯加有80%的支持率
She has an 80% approval rating in Alaska.
-全国各州之最  -80%吗
- The highest of any governor in the country-- - 80%?
她反对石油游说集团
And she got it by taking on the oil lobby
和共和党当权派  还能有如此支持率
and the Republican establishment.
当地政府层打算斥资22亿美元打造的大桥
其另一端格拉维纳岛人烟稀少
她否决了绝路桥
She's the one who killed the bridge to nowhere.
我为了那破桥和泰德·史蒂文斯争论了好几个月
I fought Ted Stevens for months on that stupid fucking bridge.
此外  她是个虔诚的基督徒
Plus, she is a devout Christian.
她儿子即将入伍前往伊拉克
She's got a son about to deploy to Iraq,
是个有五个孩子的辣妈
attractive mother of five.
-她喜欢狩猎麋鹿  -狩猎麋鹿吗
- She likes to moose hunt. - Moose hunt?
这女人会拿枪啊  约翰
This is a woman with a gun, John.
基础选民要兴奋得跳起来的
I mean, come on, the base is gonna be doing back flips.
萨尔特怎么看
What does Salter think?
他担心她是个神创论者
Uh, he's worried that she's a creationist.
所以基础选民才会喜欢她啊
Yeah, and that's exactly why the base will love her.
女性会喜欢她
Women will love her.
还有  她让你和布什的形象拉开距离
Plus, she gives you distance from bush.
更进一步  她如此与众不同
Furthermore, she's so outside the box
说不定能帮你重塑特立独行的名声
that she helps you recapture the Maverick label,
帮你赢回无党派人士
which will win back independents.
她是完美人选
She's everything we need.
你不觉得她太与众不同了吗
You don't think she might be too outside the box?
所以这才是个特立独行的决策啊
Huh. Well, that's what makes her such a Maverick choice.
选择利伯曼也是
So is picking Lieberman.
那可是相当特立独行
That'd be pretty goddamn mavericky.
先生  这是一个娱乐至死的年代
Sir, we live in the age of YouTube and the 24-hour news cycle.
否则你觉得
How else do you think a man
一个毫无建树的人
who has absolutely no major life accomplishments
是怎么大比分打败一个美国英雄的
is beating an American hero by double digits?
他只是充分发挥了自己的魅力和明星效应
He's simply sailing on his charisma and star power.
我们得创造这次竞选中的翻身机会
We need to create a dynamic moment in this campaign
否则就死定了
or we're dead.
你觉得她有那么好吗
You think she's that good?
很有可能
She could be.
五天内能审查完毕吗
And we can vet her in five days?
可以
We can.
她的审查必须和其他人的
The vet has to be as thorough for her
一样详细完善
as it was for all the other candidates.
库尔华豪斯说他能做到  那么...
Culvahouse says he can do it, so...
时间紧迫  先生
The clock is ticking, sir.
如果你在认真考虑这位阿拉斯加女州长
If you are going to seriously consider the governor of Alaska,
现在就要联系她了
you have to call her now.
州长  油价高得要人命啊
You know, Governor, these gas prices are killing us.
老天  我知道
Oh, my goodness, don't I know it.
也要我和托德的命
They're killing me and Todd, too.
你好哇
Hey, how are ya?
但是  一旦阿拉斯加获准
But once Alaska is allowed to
安全可靠地开发自身能源
very safely and responsibly develop our resources,
将能降低全美的能源支出
we'll lower cost of energy across the entire nation.
继续加油  州长
You keep giving 'em hell, Governor.
谢谢  很高兴和你谈话
Aw, thanks. Nice talking to ya.
妈妈  我们现在可以去玩过山车吗
Mom, can we go on the roller coaster now?
当然不行  宝贝
Yeah. No, of course, honey.
-布里斯托  -嗯
- Hey, Bristol? - Yeah?
帮我抱一下特里戈好吗  我要带派博玩过山车
Can you hold Trig? I'm gonna take Piper on the roller coaster.
-好的  -给
- Sure. - There you go.
好了  小家伙
There you go, buddy.
-妈妈  -等一下  宝贝
- Mom. - Just one second, hon.
我是萨拉
This is Sarah.
亚利桑那州  赛多纳
8月27日
州长  非常感谢您这么快就来了
Thank you for coming on such short notice, Governor.
一切顺利的话
Should this go according to plan,
明天早上我们将带你到麦凯恩参议员的
we will take you to meet Senator McCain at his compound
住所见他
first thing in the morning.
要是他选你做竞选搭档
Now, if he chooses you to be his running mate,
那你立刻会成为
you will instantly become
这世界上最有名的人之一
one of the most famous people on the planet.
你的过去将被调查
Your life will be investigated,
生活将受操控  扭曲
manipulated, distorted,
没有一丝的隐私
and you will lose any semblance of privacy.
你还100%确定
Knowing this, are you 100% committed
要加入吗
to going forward with this project?
肯定的
Absolutely.
我有一颗为人民服务的心
I have a servant's heart.
如果你们真认为我有利于竞选
And if you really think I can help this ticket,
真认为我有助于这个国家
if you really think I can help this country,
那肯定的  我愿意
then absolutely... I'll do this with ya.
你的私生活将受到严厉甚至无理的抨击
Your private life will be subjected to harsh, often unfair attacks.
你无法预期...
Nothing can prepare you for...
会有多卑劣  无法...
How ugly this can be. Not...
这我很清楚  这样子的
I do understand that. Here's the deal.
我在阿拉斯加经历过残酷的初选
I went through a tough primary in Alaska,
我很清楚会有多卑劣
and I know how ugly it can get.
州长  总统选举
Well, Governor, things can get
可会残酷很多
quite a bit rougher on the national stage.
这不好说  阿拉斯加可是相当残酷了
I don't know, Alaska's pretty rough.
你和麦凯恩参议员
Now, you and Senator McCain
在一些问题上政见不一
have a difference of opinion on several issues.
他反对堕胎  但如果是强奸  乱伦导致怀孕
He is pro-life, but he's in favor of exceptions
或者孕妇有生命危险时  他并不反对
in the case of rape, incest or a mother's life being at risk.
-你却不是  -没错
- You are not. - That is correct.
我反对所有堕胎
I am unapologetically pro-life.
麦凯恩参议员支持干细胞研究
Senator McCain supports stem cell research.
-而你不支持  -没错  我不支持
- You do not. - That's true, I do not.
约翰·麦凯恩不会让你摒弃自己的政见
John McCain would never ask you to contradict your beliefs,
但我们希望你全力支持他的政见
but we expect you to support his positions.
我们可能让你在竞选广告中
And we may ask you to appear in ads
拥护他的政见
advocating those positions.
你对此有意见吗
Do you have a problem with that?
完全没意见
No, I don't. Not at all.
我会全力支持麦凯恩参议员
Senator McCain can count on my full support.
我会很荣幸成为他团队的一员
I would be so proud to be a member of his team.
你不接受进化论吗
Do you reject the theory of evolution?
我父亲是名科学老师
I'm the daughter of a science teacher.
我看着我父亲的化石模型长大的
My dad showed me fossils growing up.
我了解进化论  我相信进化论
I know about evolution. I accept evolution.
但我不否认我看到上帝之手
But I will never deny that I see the hand of God
在创造这个美丽星球中的作用
in this beautiful creation that is earth.
我真的很高兴
I'm really glad that you're asking me
你们问我这类问题
these types of questions.
为什么
Why is that?
这样你们就能全面了解我
It's important that you know exactly what you're getting.
约翰  我明说了吧
John, let me be very clear.
其他审查都做了四到八周时间
Every other vet we did was over a four-to-eight-week period.
A.B.库尔华豪斯
审查律师
而这一次秘密审查只用了不到五天时间
This vet has been compiled in absolute secrecy
就完成了
in less than five days.
我明白
I understand.
审查做得这么快
Well, in doing a vet this fast,
必然有可能
there's certainly the possibility
有所遗漏
that we may have missed something.
我明白  那你觉得怎么样呢  A.B.
Yeah, I got it. What do you think, A.B.?
我对她在调查表上的回答很满意
I like many of her answers in the questionnaire.
面谈时
And in the interview,
我提的一些问题她也回答得很好
she hit some of my questions out of the park.
这样看来
Now...
比起其他的候选人
There are more potential land mines with Palin
佩林的风险更大些
than with the other choices.
她说她十几岁的女儿怀孕了
She told us she has a teen daughter who's pregnant.
这倒不会有多大影响
That should not prevent this from moving forward,
但不知道还会有什么事冒出来
but we don't know what else could pop up.
那你个人对她印象好吗
But are you impressed with her personally?
挺好的
I am.
她的经历很丰富
She has a great life story
就她目前的处境来说
and she's extremely poised and confident
她表现得很镇定  很自信
for someone in her situation.
但是这个候选人
But you have a candidate
只做了18个月州长
who's only been governor for 18 months.
在此之前  她只是一个小城的市长
Before that, she was the mayor of a small town
那城市人口才一万人
with 10,000 people.
我们主攻奥巴马没经验这点
She undercuts your best attack on Obama
会受到她的影响
that he's too inexperienced.
那正好
Well, that's played out.
我们坚持拿经验说事  也会再掉五个点
We lose by five if we stick with experience.
你觉得她准备好做副总统了吗
You think she's ready to be president?
一月二十号宣誓入职时  应该还不行
I don't think she's gonna be ready on January 20th,
但她够聪明  会准备好的
but I think she has the smarts to get there eventually.
所以你的结论是什么  A.B.
Give me the bottom line, a.B.
高风险
High risk...
高回报
High reward.
你不该告诉我
You shouldn't have told me that.
为什么
Why not?
我一生都爱冒险
I've been a risk-taker all my life.
-您好  -您好啊
- Hi. - Hi. How are ya?
好极了
Great.
谢谢你能来
Thanks so much for coming.
感谢你邀请我来你家
Thank you for having me at your beautiful house.
快请进吧
Well, come on in. Please.
萨拉  我最引以为豪的是
One of the things I'm most proud of, Sarah,
我的独立精神
is my independence.
你在阿拉斯加敢于质疑共和党当权派
And I'm very impressed with how you've bucked
这点很了不起
the Republican establishment in Alaska.
在阿拉斯加人们认为我也很独立
Well, I am wired to be kind of independent there also.
我觉得如果要真正代表人民
And I thought if I'm gonna truly run the state
治理阿拉斯加  那我就得
on behalf of the people, I'm gonna have to do it
摆脱传统政党的束缚
without that good ole boy network.
你否决了斯蒂夫的绝路桥计划  我很欣赏
I love the way you squashed Stevens' "bridge to nowhere".
我支持阿拉斯加发展经济
Yeah. I am pro-growth
支持基础设施建设
and pro-infrastructure for Alaska,
但不能以花纳税人的钱为代价
but not at the expense of the American taxpayer.
我在国会上讲过  我们需要建桥
I told congress if we wanted a bridge,
但我们会靠自己
we'd build it ourselves.
我们俩很像
You remind me of myself.
我们都是改革派
We're both reformers who are not afraid
不怕批评自己党里的一些东西
to thumb our nose at our own party.
参议员  你是美国英雄
Senator, you're an American hero.
我只是阿拉斯加的萨拉
I'm just Sarah from Alaska.
你们觉得怎样
What do you guys think?
我知道像提姆·保兰迪这样的人
I know a guy like Tim Pawlenty
你们不会觉得
isn't exactly the game-changing pick
他是改变规则的人
you all seem to think we need,
但他年轻  精力充沛
but he's young, he's energetic.
而且是坚定的保守派
He has solid conservative credentials.
有了保兰迪  基础选民会很高兴
With Pawlenty, we make the base happy.
我们也会很清楚能得到什么
And we know what the hell we're getting.
保兰迪做好了当副总统的准备
Pawlenty's ready to be president.
斯蒂夫  你觉得呢
Steve?
佩林还有很多不确定性
Well, there are unknowns with Palin,
当然  可能导致不好的结果
and certainly it could go bad.
但我要是你
But if it were me,
我宁愿冒输掉十个百分点的风险赌一把
I'd rather lose by 10 points
也不愿意因为落后一个点输掉
going for the win than lose by one point
然后回过头来说  该死
and look back and say, "God damn,"
我们应该拼死一搏的
we should have gone for the win."
我们的口号是  国家优先
Our slogan's "Country first."
利伯曼和保兰迪是体现这一口号的最佳选择
Lieberman and Pawlenty are country-first choices.
而人们会认为萨拉·佩林
Sarah Palin will be perceived
是我们谋私利的政治策略
as a self-serving political maneuver.
约翰  你可能不只输掉选举
You may not only lose the election, John.
还可能因此而坏了名声
You just might lose your reputation right along with it.
我不是为了维护名声参加竞选
I'm not running for my reputation.
我是为了做总统
I'm running to be president.
明白
Yes, sir.
有件事很重要
It is absolutely crucial
不能让任何人知道他的搭档是你
that not a single person know you're the pick.
你的突然出现能够阻止
Surprise of your announcement will stop any momentum
奥巴马通过大会演讲得到更多支持
Obama might get from his convention speech.
很英明
That's smart.
你好像一点都不受这事影响
You seem totally unfazed by all this.
都是上帝的安排
It's God's plan.
这次选举关键不在我
This election has never been about me.
关键在你们
It's about you.
你们很清楚  这次选举
You understand that in this election
我们能承担的最大风险是
the greatest risk we can take
和一群一成不变的老手
is to try the same old politics
进行一场一成不变的政治游戏
with the same old players
却期待不一样的结果
and expect a different result.
俄亥俄州代顿市
8月29日
改变会出现
Change happens.
改变会出现  因为美国人需要改变
Change happens because the American people demand it...
因为人民要求在新的时代要有新的想法
Because they rise up and insist on new ideas and new leadership
新的领导  新的政治
and new politics for a new time.
马上就见到我们的候选人了
You're about to meet our nominee.
你们是第七个和第八个知道这件事的人
You are the seventh and eighth person to know about this.
我是斯蒂夫
It's Steve.
请进
Come in.
因为我看见过...
Because I've seen it...
你们好  请进
Hi. Come on in.
我正在看奥巴马老一套花哨的演讲
I'm just watching Obama's big, fancy speech again.
州长  这是马修·斯库里
Governor, this is Matthew Scully.
-他是你主要的讲稿撰写人  -幸会
- He'll be your main speechwriter. - Nice to meet you.
这是妮可·华莱士
And this is Nicolle Wallace,
前任白宫新闻主任
former White House communications director.
你好
Hi. How are you?
这是阿拉斯加州长萨拉·佩林
And this is Governor Sarah Palin from Alaska.
久仰  恭喜你  州长
Yes, of course. Congratulations, Governor.
幸会幸会
It's a real honor to meet you.
欢迎你们加入
Great to have you on board.
过来  看看这个
Hey, come here. Look it. Look at this.
以前都不知道对手居然是希腊的神
I didn't know we were running against a Greek God.
他们真的很喜欢他
They sure do love him.
他们会更喜欢你
They're gonna love you more.
美国  我们不能走回头路
America, we cannot turn back.
莱特州立大学
俄亥俄州代顿市
8月29日
州长  你是美国副总统的候选人了
Governor, you are the nominee for the vice president of the United States.
不用再自己提包了
You will no longer be carrying your own bags.
好的  先生
Yes, sir.
永远别再叫我先生
And never call me "Sir."
你可以叫我斯蒂夫  施密特
You can call me Steve, schmidty,
光头  小白  白痴  什么都可以
Kojak, potsie, shithead-- anything you want.
我会叫你州长  或者女士
I will call you governor or ma'am.
我不骂人  所以我叫你小白吧
Well, I don't curse, so I'm gonna have to call you potsie.
很好  女士
Very good, ma'am.
这些人是特情局特工
These gentlemen are secret service agents.
他们护送你到台上
They will take you into the arena.
如果一切顺利的话
And if everything goes according to plan,
你的余生都会有他们保护
they will be with you the rest of your life.
你推开车门的瞬间
Everything's gonna change
一切都会改变
the moment you walk out that door.
准备好了吗  州长
Are you ready, Governor?
准备好了
I'm ready.
深呼吸
Breathe.
欢迎您  州长
Welcome, Governor.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢你们热情的欢迎
Thank you for that wonderful welcome.
很高兴今天能和你们一起过生日
I'm very happy today to spend my birthday with you
在代顿这个由努力 诚实的人建起的城市
and to make a historic announcement in Dayton...
我很高兴宣告一个历史性的时刻
...a city built on hard, honest work of good people.
接下来我介绍的人
The person I'm about to introduce to you
在高中曾是名出色的控球后卫
was a stand-out High School point guard,
一个关心他人的亲子会成员
a concerned citizen who became a member of the p.T.A.,
后来成为参议会议会
then a city council member...
-上帝保佑  -后来成了市长
- Say a prayer. - Then a mayor,
-现在是州长  -上帝保佑
- and now a governor. - Say a prayer.
-上帝保佑  -上帝保佑
- Say a prayer. - Say a prayer.
...庆祝女性参政
...To celebrate the anniversary of women's suffrage,
忠诚的妻子  五个孩子的母亲
a devoted wife and a mother of five.
朋友们  美国同胞们
My friends and fellow Americans,
我很荣幸地
I am very pleased
向你们介绍美国下一任
to introduce to you the next Vice President
副总统
of the United States,
阿拉斯加州长萨拉·佩林
Governor Sarah Palin of the great state of Alaska!
享受这一切
Just have fun.
这次首秀棒极了  斯蒂夫
This is a fantastic rollout, Steve.
很难想象你们保密做得这么好
I can't believe you were able to keep it a secret.
为此我没收了她孩子们的手机
I had to confiscate her kids' cell phones.
不用着急
No hurry.
-谢谢  -加油  萨拉
-Thank you. - All the way, Sarah!
谢谢你  麦凯恩参议员
And I thank you, Senator McCain,
谢谢你这么信任我
for the confidence you have placed in me.
我很荣幸能成为你的竞选搭档
Senator, I am honored to be chosen as your running mate.
本周在丹佛  人们都知道
It was rightly noted in Denver this week
希拉里在那最高的玻璃天花板上
that Hillary left 18 million cracks
玻璃天花板: 指在工作场所中隐藏的性别歧视
此处引用希拉里的败选演说
留下了1800万道裂痕
in the highest, hardest glass ceiling in America.
但其实
But it turns out
美国的女性不会就此罢手
the women of America aren't finished yet
我们要永久地粉碎这块玻璃
and we can shatter that glass ceiling once and for all.
得让她准备好大会演讲
We gotta get her ready for her convention speech.
给她安排演讲指导  国外政策专家
She'll need a vocal coach, a foreign policy expert,
发型和化妆顾问以及造型师
hair and make-up consultants and a stylist.
确实
No doubt.
*如果我是电影明星*
?And if I was a movie star?
*我会在豪车后座上*
?I'd sip honey from a pickle jar?
*偷偷抿罐头里的蜂蜜*
? In the back of my limousine?
*大家会把我当偶像*
?And they'd call me an icon?
*我会在人物杂志上*
?And I'd be looking back at you?
*回望你*
?From the cover of a "People" Magazine... ?
不  别太紧了
Not...not too tight.
*应该就是这些*
?I guess it's all for the taking... ?
我喜欢约翰尼·周的鞋子
I love these Johnny Choos.
*我妹妹说我得看看*
?My sister says I've got to see it?
*相信  我相信*
?And believe it, and I believe it...?
天啊
Oh, my gosh.
*我相信*
?I believe it?
-你觉得怎样  托德  -很棒
- What do you think, Todd? - It's cool.
-说得好  爸爸  -妈妈  你真漂亮
- Nice, dad. - Mom, you look beautiful.
看看你  看你漂亮的鞋子
Aw, hey, look at you. Look at your fancy shoes.
-妈妈 你真漂亮  -真不错
- You look so awesome, mom. - Yeah, it really looks good.
-你也不错  威洛  -谢谢
- You look great, Willow. - Thanks.
-你也是  -不错
- So do you. - So good.
瞧瞧特里戈的小衬衫
Look at Trig's little shirt.
好了  请大家跟我来
Okay, if you all come with me,
该拍竞选照片了
it's time for your campaign photos.
-拜拜  妈妈  -走吧  孩子们
Bye, mom. - Okay. Let's go, guys.
-待会儿见  宝贝  -好
- See you in a bit, hon. - Yeah.
州长  他们是新成员
Governor, this is your new staff--
这是塔克·埃斯库  高级媒体顾问
Tucker Eskew, senior media advisor.
-幸会  -幸会
- It's a pleasure. - Nice to meet you.
这是克里斯·爱德华兹  团队副总管
Chris Edwards, your deputy chief of staff.
-你好  -你好
- Hi. - Hi.
这是我的丈夫   马克·华莱士
And my husband, Mark Wallace,
前任驻联合国大使
former ambassador to the United Nations.
他将任高级顾问
He'll be a senior advisor.
州长  很荣幸能加入您的团队
We're all honored to be on your team, Governor.
-这是我的荣幸  -请坐吧
- The honor is all mine. - Shall we sit?
州长  我们的第一项工作是
Well, our first order of business, Governor,
了解一下你还有没有
is we need to find out
我们还不知道的事情
if there are any unexpected surprises.
媒体会对你的过去刨根问底
The press are gonna be digging deep into your past,
所以我们要做好回答的准备
so we need to prepare answers about your background.
天啊
Oh, gosh.
我想不出还有什么没有公开的
I can't think of anything I haven't already disclosed.
瓦西拉镇的图书管理员声称
The Wasilla librarian claims that as mayor
她任镇长时试图禁止图书  属实吗
she tried to ban books. Is that true?
关于特里戈并非她亲生的指控是什么情况
What about the allegations that Trig is not really her child?
她是否加入了使用灵言的五旬节教会
Did she attend a pentecostal church where they speak in tongues?
源自1901-1906年间在美国的五旬节运动出现的基督新教教派
强调直接灵感  信奉信仰治疗
我们采访了对佩林作资格审查的相关人士
This source we talked to intimately involved in Palin's vetting
他们承认除了与
admitted that aside from those they talked to
被卷入所谓"州警门"的人进行了谈话
involved in so-called troopergate,
08年佩林曾试图让公共安全专员莫奈甘开除前妹夫伍登的州警职务
莫奈甘拒绝后被开除
再没跟阿拉斯加的任何品德证人谈过
they didn't talk to any character witnesses in Alaska--
为什么审查糟成这样
Why was the vet so bad?
坦白说  审查时间太紧
Listen, granted, he only had a few days,
不过库尔华豪斯帮她澄清了
but Culvahouse did clear her.
拿什么  维基百科吗
Oh, with what? Wikipedia?
资格审查一点都不彻底
There's no way this vet was thorough.
什么  漏了什么
What? What did he miss?
他把"州警门"  "绝路桥"都翻出来了
He had troopergate. He had bridge to nowhere.
没人去阿拉斯加采访她的同事和敌人
No one went to Alaska to interview her colleagues, her enemies.
也没有什么政审
There was no political vet whatsoever.
这些指控都是狗屁
These charges are such bullshit.
特里戈不是她的孩子吗
I mean, Trig isn't her baby?
灵言
What, speaking in tongues?
-她的确说  -我不管
- She does. - I don't care.
宪法第一修正案在这里没用吗
Is the First Amendment no longer law here?
美国宪法第一修正案指出公民拥有新闻言论自由
她无权选择宗教信仰吗
Is she not entitled to her religious beliefs?
你没抓住重点  里克
You're missing the point, Rick.
约翰正遭受猛烈抨击  被指选择不负责任
John is getting slammed for making an irresponsible choice.
-我们选中了她  -不  是你们俩选中了她
- We picked her. - No, you two picked her,
拍拍她屁股  把她推出去
then slapped her on the butt and shoved her out there
站在"国家优先"的横幅下
under a banner saying "Country first!"
你真是个蠢货  马克
You're a real prick, Mark.
-去你的  施密特  -去你的
- Fuck you, Schmidt! - Fuck you!
好了好了  我们把这关过了
All right, all right! Let's just get through this.
来吧
Come on.
州警门  什么
Troopergate. What--?
阿拉斯加州公共安全专员
The Alaska safety commissioner
声称自己被撤职是因为没有开除
is claiming that he was fired because he wouldn't fire
佩林的妹夫  州警迈克·伍登
Palin's brother-in-law, trooper Mike Wooten.
对州警伍登的指控是什么
And what were the charges against trooper Wooten?
除了他跟佩林妹妹离婚的事实吗
Besides the fact that he was divorcing Palin's sister?
对  我们有没有资料显示
Yes. Do we have any information that shows
州警伍登应该被开除
trooper Wooten should have been fired?
有  伍登被指控
Yeah, Wooten was accused of drinking
执勤时在警车内饮酒
from an open container from his police car,
用泰瑟枪电击11岁继子
tasering his 11-year-old stepson,
还有非法射杀驼鹿
and illegally shooting a moose without a permit.
天哪
Jesus Christ.
让阿拉斯加议会统一口径
Okay, coordinate all responses with their Alaskan council.
要把这事控制在当地
Let's try to keep it a local matter.
绝路桥  这个我们应该很拿手
Bridge to nowhere. I thought we were good on this.
她当选后压下了这个项目
She had the project squashed after she was elected,
但她是靠支持建桥当选的
but ran on a platform to build the bridge.
大变脸[指改变政治立场]
It's a huge flip-flop.
该死的
God damn it.
她为什么没告诉我们
How could she not tell us that?
阿拉斯加独立党又他妈是什么东西
What the fuck is the Alaska Independence Party
她是党内成员吗
and was she ever a member of it?
阿拉斯加独立党是个政党  唯一党纲是
The A.I.P. Is a political party whose sole platform
阿拉斯加脱离联邦
is the secession of Alaska from the union.
挺有趣的啊
Well, ain't that a hoot?
她是党内成员吗
Now, was she ever a member of it?
是吗
Well?
我们知道托德·佩林多年来都是党内成员
We know Todd Palin was a member for many years.
我们无法确定她是不是
We can't confirm if she was ever a member.
好的  现在就联系你在阿拉斯加的人
Okay. Call our people in Alaska right now
查出她是不是
and find out if she was.
现在阿拉斯加是凌晨3点
半夜连电话都不会响吗
The phones don't work there at night?!
我们正遭受攻击  朋友们
We're under attack here, people!
你们得加把劲
You're gonna have to raise your game.
我敢保证奥巴马的人
I can assure you that Obama's people
全扑在这些事上
are all over this shit.
在过去的24小时内  我被国内媒体
In the last 24 hours, I have been asked questions
问了许多蛮横  恶心的问题
by the national media that are outrageous and disgusting.
有人问我  她上次生产时
I have been asked when her amniotic fluid
羊水是什么时候破的
started to leak with regard to her last birth.
太无耻了
It's shameful.
那是什么时候破的
So when did it start leaking?
她与石油公司对抗
She's fought the oil companies.
与腐败的特殊利益集团较量
She's taken on corrupt special interests.
这些指控完全是性别歧视
These accusations are totally sexist.
我这辈子没见过哪位候选人
Never in my life have I seen a candidate
被自由派媒体攻击成这样
more attacked by the liberal media.
诽谤一个接一个
Smear after smear after smear.
确定我们要这么做吗
Are you sure we have to do this?
我告诉布里斯托时  她哭个不停
Bristol couldn't stop crying when I told her.
这个明天就会见报
It's going to have come out tomorrow
不管我们发不发声明  州长
with or without our statement, Governor.
积极的一面是
A positive from this
考虑到布里斯托的孕期
is that given the timing of Bristol's pregnancy,
特里戈不可能是她的孩子
it makes it physically impossible for Trig to be her baby.
我们就能平息那个荒谬的谣言
So we can put that absurd rumor to rest.
我们为布里斯托生孩子的决定而感到骄傲
"We're proud of Bristol's decision to have her baby
更为能成为祖父母而感到骄傲
and even prouder to become grandparents."
未成年的女儿怀孕了
We're not proud
我们才不会感到骄傲  玛丽亚
that our teenage daughter is pregnant, Maria.
我也不想让人们觉得
And I don't want to send a message that teen pregnancy
青少年怀孕是值得骄傲的事
is something to be proud of.
我想把这句去掉
I want that line out.
好的  州长  我现在就改
Of course, Governor. I'll change it right away.
在竞选现场我们看到
Governor Palin's 17-year-old daughter Bristol
佩林州长17岁的女儿布里斯托抱着弟弟特里戈
has been seen holding her baby brother Trig at campaign events.
美国人民今天才知道
What the American people didn't know until today
布里斯托已有了五个月的身孕
is that Bristol is five months pregnant.
她的父母发表了如下声明
Her parents issued this statement:
我们为布里斯托生孩子的决定而感到骄傲
"We're proud of Bristol's decision to have her baby."
我明明说了把这句去掉
I specifically wanted that line taken out,
你却一字不差地放出来
and you ran it without changing a word.
你说得对
You're absolutely right.
竞选团队对此全权负责
The campaign takes full responsibility on this.
玛丽亚将当面向你道歉
Maria's gonna personally apologize to you.
怎么会这么冒失
How the flip did this happen?
麦凯恩参议员有时候
Senator McCain is somewhat
会意气用事
a fly-by-the-seat-of-his-pants type of guy,
所以有时竞选团队会有点混乱
and it does occasionally create a little chaos in the campaign.
我希望玛丽亚辞职
Well, I want Maria gone.
州长  这是失误  玛丽亚很难过
Governor, this was a mistake. Maria feels terrible.
她是名优秀的新闻发言人
She's an excellent press secretary.
我17岁的女儿正被
My 17-year-old daughter is being made fun of
国内每个脱口秀主持取笑
by every talk show host in the country.
我要玛丽亚辞职
I want Maria gone, period.
好的  州长  她不会再来了
Of course, Governor. She's gone.
好了
Done.
谁去打这通电话
Who makes that call?
你
That'd be you.
如果约翰·麦凯恩这位72岁高龄
The idea that if something happened to John McCain
并得过两次黑素瘤的候选人意外去世
who is 72 years old and who has had two bouts with melanoma,
接任总统的将会是她
and she could step into the presidency--
太荒谬了
It's just ridiculous.
事情的真相是  瑞秋
The real sequence, Rachel,
她起初赞成造桥
is she said "Please" and "Thank you,"
上台后国会刚一取消造桥计划
and then "Thanks, but no thanks,"
她就也随声附和说不要造桥
only when the Congress had de-authorized the bridge...
你好  州长  我就过来报个到
Hi, Governor. I just wanted to check in,
确保你还好
make sure you're doing okay.
约翰·麦凯恩是否应该考虑换掉萨拉·佩林
Should John McCain consider replacing Sarah Palin
作为共和党候选人
on the GOP ticket?
我想跟媒体谈谈
I want to talk to the press.
我要澄清这件事
I want to set the record straight on this stuff.
我去帮特里戈穿睡衣
I'll just go put Trig's PJ's on.
-好了  宝贝  -帮你穿睡衣
- There you go, baby. - Just gonna put your PJ's on.
我们不希望你跟任何人谈
Now, we don't want you to talk to anyone
直到共和党大会结束
until after the convention
因为没人了解你
because no one knows anything about you.
如果你回应了这些荒谬的指控
If you answer these ridiculous allegations,
就是把自己定义为辩护立场
you'll be defining yourself in a defensive posture.
媒体不正在这样定义我的吗
But isn't the press defining me right now?
没有哪个新闻报道能延续48小时以上的
No news story lasts more than 48 hours any more.
新闻不被人铭记
News is no longer meant to be remembered.
而是仅供娱乐
It's just entertainment.
如果你能在共和党大会上表现出色
So if you hit your convention speech out of the park,
下一波新闻就是萨拉·佩林的回归
the next news cycle will be the comeback of Sarah Palin.
我能做好
Yeah. I can do that.
每个人都听说了你的疯狂故事
Now, everyone's heard a lot of crazy stories about you.
现在是时候由你告诉世界  真实的自己
Now it's time for you to tell the world who you really are.
告诉麦凯恩参议员  我不会令他失望
You tell Senator McCain I won't let him down.
晚上好  这里是圣保罗的共和党选举人代表大会
And good evening from the G.O.P. Convention in St. Paul.
所有目光都将聚焦在麦凯恩参议员的
All eyes will be on Senator McCain's
副总统人选  萨拉·佩林
V.P. choice, Governor Sarah Palin,
在本次大会上的登台演讲
when she takes the stage at the R.N.C.
她很可能从未见过如此
She's likely never seen a night
充满预期
fraught with so much anticipation,
期待和压力的夜晚
expectation and pressure.
共和党全国代表大会
9月3日
食物很糟  但我听说伊拉克的更糟
The food's terrible, but I hear it's gonna be worse in Iraq.
-我儿子真勇敢  -加油  妈妈
- My boy's so brave. - Come on, mom.
谢谢你邀请我  佩林女士
Thank you for inviting me, Mrs. Palin.
谢谢你剪了头发  莱威
Thank you for cutting your mullet, Levi.
非常感谢
I really appreciate it.
一开始不想剪的
I didn't really want to at first,
但我觉得现在看上去好多了
but I think it looks way better now.
我也这么觉得
I think it does, too.
抱歉打断一下
Sorry to interrupt,
佩林一家该就座了
but the Palins need to go to their seats.
-再见  妈妈  -好
- Bye, mom. - Okay.
我不知道  不知道
I don't know. I don't know.
她没问题的
Hey, she's gonna be fine.
-真的吗  -绝对
- Really? - Absolutely.
她没问题吧
Is she gonna be okay?
我更担心一对一辩论
I'm more concerned about one on ones.
多糟
How bad?
我不确定她对外交政策了解多少
I'm not sure how much she knows about foreign policy.
她不知道为什么南北朝鲜是两个国家
She didn't know why North and South Korea were different countries.
好吧  我们别让媒体靠近她
Okay, let's keep the press away from her.
我们还有五天时间让她熟悉形势
We have five days to bring her up to speed.
她没问题的
She'll be fine.
她五分钟后上台  我去准备一下
She's on in five minutes. I've gotta get up there.
好运
Good luck.
选择萨拉·佩林州长
In choosing Governor Sarah Palin
作为竞选伙伴
as his running mate,
约翰·麦凯恩为将来做了选择
John McCain has chosen for the future.
佩林州长代表着新一代
Governor Palin represents a new generation.
她已然是美国最成功的州长之一
She's already one of the most successful governors
而且是最受欢迎的
in America and the most popular.
让我们选择约翰·麦凯恩和萨拉·佩林
Let's get John McCain and Sarah Palin elected,
震撼华盛顿
and let's shake up Washington
推动这个国家前进
and move this country forward!
你能行
You're gonna do great.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
阿拉斯加州长
the Governor of Alaska
美利坚合众国下一任副总统
and the next Vice President of the United States,
萨拉·佩林
Sarah Palin!
谢谢
Thank you.
主席先生  各位代表
Mr. Chairman, delegates,
美国人民
and fellow citizens,
我很荣幸被提名为
I will be honored to accept your nomination
美利坚合众国的副总统
for Vce President of the United States.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们的总统候选人
Our nominee is a man
在军队服役22年
who wore the uniform of his country for 22 years
并拒绝对我们在伊拉克的部队失去信心
and refused to break faith with those troops in Iraq
现在伊拉克战局已胜利在望
who now have brought victory within sight.
好  很好  她真的不错
Good, good. She's really good.
四月份的时候
We were so blessed in April.
我和托德有了一个小儿子
Todd and I welcomed our littlest one into the world--
非常漂亮的小男孩特里戈
a perfectly beautiful baby boy named Trig.
需要特殊照顾的孩子们
Children with special needs
激发出更加特别的爱
inspire a very, very special love.
她太棒了
She's amazing.
我们这个国家所有
To the families of special needs children
需要特殊照顾的孩子家庭  我要对你们说
all across this country, I have a message for you.
我向你们保证  如果我们当选
I pledge to you that if we are elected,
你们在白宫将会有一位朋友和辩护者
you will have a friend and advocate in the White House.
她太棒了
She's incredible!
在我成为伟大的
Before I became Governor
阿拉斯加州州长时
of the great state of Alaska...
我是自己家乡的镇长
I was mayor of my hometown.
我想一个小镇的镇长
I guess a small-town mayor
类似于社区组织者
is sort of like a community organizer.
讽刺奥巴马没有经验  只当过社区组织者
但是有具体的责任
Except that you have actual responsibilities.
终于知道为什么叫她"萨拉梭子鱼"了
Now I know why they call her "Sarah barracuda."
我喜欢那些冰球妈妈
I love those hockey moms.
你们知道
You know they say the difference
冰球妈妈和斗牛犬的区别是什么吗
between a hockey mom and a pit bull?
前者擦口红
Lipstick.
她刚刚这句是临场发挥
She just came up with that.
加入我们  帮助美国
Join our cause and help America
选出一位伟人担任下一届
elect a great man as the next President
美利坚合众国的总统
of the United States.
谢谢
Thank you.
愿上帝保佑美国
And God bless America.
-干得好  -不能更好了
- Great job! You did a great job! - Couldn't have gone better.
-恭喜  -天哪
- Congratulations. - My God!
她没有用提词器
She did it without a teleprompter.
演讲到一半就坏了
It broke halfway through her speech.
-开玩笑的吧  -没有
- You're kidding. - No.
如果明晚出状况  我就完了
If that happens to me tomorrow night, I'm fucked.
我们能赢
We can win this!
谢谢来电  我们接受信用卡付款
Thank you for calling. Yes, we do take credit cards.
-很高兴...  -我拉到五百块
- I'd be happy to... - I've got $500.
我们对每一分钱心存感激
We're grateful for every dollar we get.
是的  萨拉·佩林这周将在佛罗里达做演讲
Yes, Sarah Palin will be giving a speech in Florida this week.
谢谢
Thanks.
好了
Hey. Here we go.
-谢谢你来  -我喜欢你
- Thanks for coming. - I love you.
-天哪  真疯狂  -他们真喜欢她
- God, this is crazy. - I know, they really love her.
你好
How are ya? Hey.
-你叫什么名字  -我叫萨拉
- Hey, what's your name? - I'm Sarah.
-萨拉  -是啊
- Sarah? - Yeah.
我也叫萨拉  太神了
That's my name, too. That's amazing!
我知道
I know.
谢谢你过来
Hey, thanks for coming out.
谢谢  我们从前到哪都不受欢迎
Thank you. We never felt welcome to go anywhere
直到看到你的演讲
before we saw you give that speech.
谢谢  太感谢了
Oh, thank you. Thanks so much.
看看你  我想看我儿子特里戈
Look at you. I want to look at how handsome
长大成人后能有多帅
my son Trig's gonna be when he's all grown up.
她知道不能靠政府解决问题
She understands that you can't solve problems with government,
政府才是问题
that government is the problem.
她讲到自己的信仰时  看得出是认真的
When she talks about her faith, you can tell it's for real.
她讲到枪支问题时  看得出是认真的
When she talks about guns, you can tell it's for real.
我也有五个孩子
I've got five kids, too,
她还有一种特质
and there's something about her--
她真心跟我说话  没人愿意跟我说话
she's talking to me. And nobody talks to me.
CNN民调显示  我们跟奥巴马打平了
CNN has us even with Obama.
-开玩笑吗  -盖乐普民调  我们上升了五个点
- Are you kidding me? - Hey, Gallup has us up by five.
她帮我们得到的正是我们需要的
She's given us exactly what we needed.
前几天我们得到了更多资金
We've made more money in the last few days
这几天拿到的资金都超过上月合计了
than we did all last month.
我一辈子都没见过这么热情的选民
I've never seen crowds like this in my life.
-民众喜爱她  -她比奥巴马更耀眼
- They love her. - She's a bigger star than Obama.
我们这下赢定了
We can really win this thing.
我能理解你们的心情
I really understand your frustr--
抱歉  诸位  今天没有采访安排
I'm sorry, pool. It's not gonna happen today.
抱歉
Sorry.
-只要五分钟  -别小瞧媒体
- Five minutes! - Views matter.
你知道托德·佩林是爱斯基摩人吗
Did you know that Todd Palin is an Eskimo?
是吗  斯蒂夫  挺有意思
Oh, yeah, Steve? That's really interesting.
真的  他是尤皮克支爱斯基摩人
Seriously, he's a Yupik Eskimo.
如果我们不尽快安排她与媒体接触
We're gonna take some serious blowback from the press
记者的意见会越来越大
if we don't let them speak to her soon.
-他们真会抓狂的  -我知道
- They're really getting pissed. - I know, yeah.
我不知道她会如何应对
Well, I don't know how ready she is.
尼科尔  你多虑了
Nicolle, you worry too much.
大家都知道她对外交政策缺乏了解
We always knew she'd be weak on foreign policy.
我们会尽快帮她搞定
We'll get her up to speed.
斯蒂夫  我觉得除了外交政策
Steve, I don't think foreign policy
还存在其他问题
is her only weakness.
抱歉  打扰你一下
Sorry to bother you, Governor.
州长  现在方便谈谈吗
Is now a okay time to talk?
福音战士: 致力于为他人祈祷的基督教徒
可以  我刚刚在读福音战士发来的邮件
Sure, I'm just reading the e-mails from the Prayer Warriors.
他们真有意思
These guys are awesome.
我想告诉你
I just want to take a moment to inform you
麦凯恩对你那天的表现非常满意
of how thrilled Senator McCain is.
你所做的一切
You're exceeding his wildest expectation
完全超出他先前的预期
for what a running mate could achieve.
很高兴听他这么说
I am so happy to hear that.
从政以来  我还是第一次
These are the largest crowds I've ever seen
见到这般热情的民众
in my entire political career, ever.
真的吗  我就是
Really? Yeah, I just--
喜欢跟人们聊天
I just love talking to people on the rope lines,
倾听他们的困难
getting to hear their problems.
我真的很感动
It's-- it's really moving to me.
人们也能体会到
Well, you know, that comes across.
州长  你帮我们力挽狂澜
You're a transformative figure, Governor.
你完全可以成为里根第二
You-- you could be the party's next Ronald Reagan.
上帝  我
Holy jeez, I--
其实  他是我的偶像  所以
yeah, he's-- he's my hero, so...
他也是我的偶像
Mine, too. So, uh...
接下来  我们将会安排你接受一些采访
The next step is just-- we're gonna start doing some interviews.
太好了  我迫不及待想跟媒体交流
Great. I've been dying to talk to the press.
而且  我觉得可以帮到你们
Also, I feel like I could really help you there.
在阿拉斯加  我对媒体一直持有开放态度
I've always been very, very open with the press in Alaska.
我们没让你接受采访有我们的考虑
The reasoning behind holding you back
整个媒体界一致倒向奥巴马阵营
is the entire press corps is in the tank for Obama,
他们只想用尖锐的问题令你出洋相
so all they want in life is to trip you up with obscure questions.
-刁难问题  -刁难问题
- Gotcha questions. - Gotcha questions.
所以我们希望等你准备充分一切就绪后
So we just want to make sure you're fully prepped
再跟他们见面
before we unleash them.
会有阿拉斯加的报纸采访吗
What about the local Alaska papers?
没有地方报刊
There are no local papers any more.
你的言语将即时出现在国家媒体上
Anything you say goes national the instant you say it.
我懂了
Yeah, got it.
我觉得最好的准备方式
Okay, so I think the best way to prep would
就是先过一遍样题
just be to go through some sample questions.
行  开始吧
Sure, let's do it.
那我们先从简单的入手
Um, let's start with something simple.
面对英国国内强烈的反伊战呼声
Uh... how do you plan on maintaining our alliance with Great Britain on Iraq,
如何维系与英国的联盟关系
even though support for the war there is at an all-time low?
我觉得美国与女王一直保持着密切的关系
I think the United States has always maintained a great relationship with the Queen.
约翰·麦凯恩将继续与她进行公开对话
And John McCain will continue to have an open dialogue with her.
州长
Uh, Governor,
女王不是英国政府首脑
the Queen is not the head of government in England.
她是国家元首
She's the head of state.
那谁是政府首脑
Well, then, who's the head of government?
首相
The Prime Minister.
兰迪·舒尼曼
斯蒂夫·拜根
外交政策顾问
随传随到
You rang?
真是及时雨
The cavalry has arrived.
-感谢二位光临  请进  -你猜对了
- Thank you, gentlemen. Come on in. - You bet.
好
Yeah.
我
Well, I, uh--
我认为我们可以先给州长
I think we should start by prepping the Governor
介绍俄罗斯的经济政策
with Russian economic policy
跟普京上台前美苏"后冷战时代"有联系
as it relates to post-cold war tensions during the pre-Putin era.
我觉得我们可以更简单一点
I was thinking something a little bit simpler.
要多简单
How much simpler?
这里是德国
This is Germany.
是一战与二战的主要同盟国
They were the primary antagonists during World War I and World War II.
第二次世界大战间
And in World War II,
它与日本  意大利结为轴心国阵营
they were aligned with Japan and Italy to form what was known as the Axis.
现今我们正处于"三场战争"
Currently, we're in the middle of what I like to call "the three wars".
阿富汗战争  伊拉克战争  全球反恐战争
That's Afghanistan, Iraq, and the global war on terror.
州长  需要休息一下吗
Governor, would you-- would you like to take a break?
别  蛮有意思的
No way. This is flippin' awesome.
就阿富汗而言  9/11事件后
Now, with Afghanistan, after 9/11...
已为其家庭建起一道保护墙
... already put a protective wall up around the family,
对个别成员的保密尤甚
especially the key players.
萨拉·佩林的女儿布莉丝托如今已有身孕
Look at Bristol, Sarah Palin's daughter, who is pregnant.
我们见过她
We've seen her,
和她男友莱威
we've seen her boyfriend Levi,
也就是孩子的父亲
the father of her child,
但我们还未能向当事人求证
but we haven't really gotten to talk to them
是谁最先提出结婚
about whose idea it was to get married
另外
and why, for example,
为什么莱威在个人空间说不想要小孩
Levi on his MySpace page - says he doesn't want kids...
这不是什么
That isn't anybody's--
他们为什么不让我静一静
Why won't they just leave me alone?
我受够了
I'm so tired of it.
欺负小女孩的人都不是什么好东西
Any grownup who makes fun of a teenage girl is a terrible person.
宝贝  忘记她说的话  好吗
And we'll forget what she said, honey, okay?
好吗
Okay?
我的邮箱被黑了
My e-mails were hacked.
我了解  州长
I know, Governor,
我们正努力维护  我向你保证
and we're on it. I promise you.
你知不知道我女儿的手机号
Did you know that my daughter's cell phone
在网上被曝光  她常接到骚扰电话
is online and she's getting crank calls?
你知不知道我的家人正遭受威胁
Did you know that my family is being threatened?
州长  你有权生气  我很抱歉
Governor, you have every right to be upset, and I am sorry.
我已经跟特勤局取得联系
I've already contacted Secret Service
他们表示会加强防护
and they're gonna increase security.
你能不能
Can you--
能否麻烦你保护我的邮件  斯蒂夫
can you protect my e-mails, Steve?
你  或者竞选至少保证这一点
Can you-- can this campaign at least do that?
查理·吉布森很专业
Charlie Gibson is good,
他必定会提一些比较有深度的问题
so I'm sure the questions will have some depth.
像能源这种你擅长的话题
Don't be afraid to elaborate if it's a subject you feel comfortable with,
可以展开论述
like energy.
你没事吧  州长
Are you okay, Governor?
为什么我们在阿拉斯加没动静
Why aren't there any McCain-Palin lawn signs in Alaska?
因为奥巴马先生
Well, Mr. Obama
手上的竞选经费是我们的5倍
has five times the money we have.
5倍呀  另外
Five times, and...
阿拉斯加只有3票
Alaska is only three electoral votes,
完全在共和党的掌控之中
and it's solid red.
我不知道家乡民众会不会把票投给我
I'm concerned about my standing back home.
托德跟我都听到一些传言
Todd and I are hearing things,
而我又没法与阿拉斯加媒体交流
and I can't talk to the Alaskan press.
你听到什么传言
What are you hearing?
谣言  反正没好话
Things. None of it's good.
你能调查一下我的民众支持率吗
Can you at least do a poll to check my approval rating there?
州长  一次民调要花6万美元经费
Governor, that would cost the campaign $60,000.
知道我目前的支持率
I'd feel a heck of a lot better
能让我好受不少
if I knew where I was at.
那好  为了让你舒心
Absolutely. We will do the poll
我们会做这次民调  仅此一次
for your peace of mind, just this once.
很好  谢谢
Great. Thank you.
现在可以继续准备查理·吉布森的问题吗
So, can we get back to prepping Charlie Gibson?
当然  我没问题  开始吧
Sure, I'm ready. Let's do it.
-准备好了吗  -准备好了
- You ready? - Yes.
你认为美联储
Do you think the Fed
对贝尔斯登破产处理正确吗[08年金融危机]
did the right thing in their dealing with the Bear Stearns collapse?
经济形势日益严峻
Our economy is hurting,
而联邦政府却无力
and the federal government has not
为国家提供一个健全完备的监督体系
provided the sound oversight that we need and that we deserve.
我认为我们需要将瓦西拉的民生
I think we need a little bit of reality from Wasilla Main Street
传达给华盛顿
there brought to Washington, D.C.,
让人民了解
so that the people there can understand
工薪家庭如何看待联邦政府的官僚主义
how the average working-class family is viewing bureaucracy in the federal government.
州长
Governor...
你知道美联储是什么吗
Do you know what the Fed is?
你指哪方面  查理
In what respect, Charlie?
不  这次是我本人提问
No, no. This is me, Steve,
你知道美联储是什么吗
asking do you know what the Fed is?
国家联邦储备系统
Stands for the Federal Reserve System.
请别急着记  先听我讲
No, please. Don't write, just listen.
美联储负责我国货币政策
The Fed is responsible for all monetary policy in the United States.
任何涉及美联储或贝尔斯登的问题
On any Fed or Bear Stearns question,
只需回答美联储采取了及时有效的救助措施
just say the Fed took the appropriate action that was needed at the time.
好吗
Okay?
知道了
Got it.
你长子将于下周随军入驻伊拉克
Your oldest son is proudly heading off to Iraq next week.
此刻谁是你的首要敌人
Who do you see as the primary enemy at this point?
激进的伊斯兰极端分子
Radical Islamist extremists.
你能具体说明吗
Can you be more specific?
那些决意摧毁我们国家的恐怖分子
The terrorists who are hell-bent on destroying our nation.
州长  你知道为何在伊拉克驻兵吗
Governor, do you know why we're in Iraq?
因为萨达姆·侯赛因
Because Saddam Hussein
在9月11日对我们进行恐怖袭击
attacked us on 9/11.
不是  不
No. No, uh,
911的肇事者是"基地"组织
Al-Qaeda attacked us on 9/11.
不是萨达姆·侯赛因
Not Saddam Hussein.
是"基地"组织干的
No, it was Al-Qaeda.
所以我们才派兵驻扎阿富汗
And that's why we're in Afghanistan.
你知道阿富汗战争
Do you know the primary differences between the war in Afghanistan
与伊拉克战争最大的区别在哪吗
and the war in Iraq?
失陪一下
Um, excuse us for a moment.
能为我再准备一点阿富汗方面的资料吗
Can I get some more information about Afghanistan?
当然  州长
Of course, Governor.
-要不取消采访吧  -不行
- Should we cancel? - We can't.
福克斯都开始对我们施压
Even Fox is pounding us for hiding her.
-取消就死定了  -你们面试她的时候
- We'd get murdered. - When you interviewed her,
都没问过国家安全问题吗
didn't you ask her about national security?
外交政策  国内政策
Foreign policy, domeicic policy?
我以为库尔华豪斯会问
I thought Culvahouse would cover that.
那你们都问了她什么
So what did you ask her?
我只是  我们问她
I just-- we talked about
她是否愿意全力支持约翰
if she would back John's positions
就算约翰的某些立场与她的相冲突
when they conflicted with hers
还有  她是否做好改变人生的准备
or if she was prepared for her life to change.
没问政策问题
There were no policy questions.
你们没细问是因为你们想让她通过
You guys didn't grill her because you wanted it to work.
我不负责审查  妮可
I wasn't in charge of the vet, Nicolle.
她演技超棒  对吗
She's a great actress, right?
绝对一流
Oh, the best.
干嘛不直接替她准备一些台词呢
Why don't we just give her some lines?
这些是我认为查理最可能提出的问题
I've come up with a list of questions that I think Charlie's most likely to ask.
只要你把回答记下
If you memorize these answers,
我保证你可以顺利过关
I'm sure you're going to nail this interview.
你怎么知道他会问这些
How do you know he'll ask these?
我曾任白宫新闻主任
I was the White House communications director.
我的工作就是预测问题
It's my job to figure out the questions.
萨斯卡什维利
"Shushkashvili."
萨卡什维利  格鲁吉亚总统
Saakashvili, the President of Georgia.
萨斯卡什维利
Shashkashvili.
萨卡什维利
Saakashvith--
-萨卡什维利  -萨卡什-维利
- Saakashvili. - Saakash-vili.
我想就国家安全状况提几个具体问题
Let me ask you about some specific national security situations.
好的
Sure.
首先是关于俄罗斯与格鲁吉亚
Let's start with Russia and Georgia.
你认为美国应该维护
Do you believe the United States should try to restore
格鲁吉亚在南奥赛梯与阿伯卡茨的主权吗
Georgian sovereignty over South Ossetia and Abkhazia?
首先  我们仍将继续
First off, we're gonna continue
与萨卡什维利保持良好关系
good relations with Saakashvili there.
我前几天刚与他通过话
I was able to speak with him the other day,
我们应该同时密切关注俄罗斯的动向
and we've gotta keep an eye on Russia.
俄罗斯
For Russia
无故对一个弱小民主国家
to have exerted such pressure in terms of invading
发起进攻
a smaller Democratic country unprovoked
实在是无法接受  而且我们
is unacceptable, and we have...
你认为俄方是无故吗
You believe unprovoked?
-对  -我相信俄方无故
- Yes. - I do, I do believe unprovoked.
我们必须对俄罗斯提高警惕
And we have to keep our eye on Russia...
镁光灯一开她就进入状态
She's a red-light performer.
关注领导层的意向
...under the leadership there.
你如何解读
What insight
俄罗斯近期  特别是近两周的动作
into Russian actions, particularly in the last couple of weeks,
阿拉斯加的地理位置是否让你有不同看法
does the proximity of this state give you?
它是我们的邻居
They're our next-door neighbors.
站在阿拉斯加你可以直接望见俄罗斯
And you can actually see Russia from land here in Alaska.
你认为伊朗核问题
Do you consider a nuclear Iran...
-该死  -对以色列构成严重威胁吗
- Damn it. - ...to be an existential threat to Israel?
从我家就可以看到俄罗斯
And I can see Russia from my house.
我相信温室效应由人类活动所致
I believe global warming is caused by man.
我相信只是因为上帝想把我们搂紧一点
And I believe it's just God hugging us closer.
我不同意布什主义
I don't agree with the Bush Doctrine.
布什政府在国家安全政策和对外交往中
遵循"美国利益至上"和"以实力求和平"两大原则
我不知道那是什么玩意
And I don't know what that is.
她开始还没意识到
She initially did not understand this,
而我也觉得人们能自己作出判断
and I think that people can make what they want of it,
但我或其他人可以确信
but was I, or anone, confident that
萨拉·佩林能够胜任美国总统吗
Sarah Palin now has the wherewithal to be president of the United States?
我不这么认为
I don't think so.
我的一位保守党朋友跟我在电话里说
A conservative friend called me up and said
"我不能这么做
"I just can't do it.
我不确定自己会不会把票投给奥巴马
I don't know if I'm voting for Obama,
但我没法投给她
but I can't have her--
她不该出现在华盛顿  更别说白宫了"
She shouldn't be in Washington, let alone the White House."
州长
Governor.
佩林州长
Governor Palin.
我们应该准备一下凯蒂·柯丽克的访问
We really should prep for your Katie Couric interview.
行
Fine.
我写了一份有关雷曼兄弟垮台
I wrote a brief synopsis on the collapse of Lehman Brothers
与经济危机的概要
and the financial crisis.
如果你把这份文件背熟
If you internalize this document,
应该就能应付金融救市的基本问题了
you should be able to field basic questions about the bail-out.
州长
Governor...
道琼斯指数下跌了500点
The Dow just dropped 500 points.
雷曼摇摇欲坠
Lehman is collapsing.
世界经济正处于崩盘的边缘
The world economy is on the bring of collapse.
所以我确信访问里会涉及金融救市问题
So I am pretty sure the bail-out is going to come up--
那好
Okay. Um...
要不你先准备下我们再开始
Wh don't we come back to it after we've warmed up a bit?
我把凯蒂最有可能提的问题列了出来
I've put together a list of the questions... that Katie's most likely to ask.
我曾同凯蒂共事过
I used to work with Katie,
我知道她会提流产的问题
and I know she'll ask about abortion.
斯蒂夫做了阿拉斯加的民调没有
Did Steve do the Alaska poll yet?
应该正在进行中
I think it's being done as we speak.
我猜他根本就没做
Bet he didn't even do it.
要不我们试着过几道问题吧
Can we try and get through just a few questions?
我知道你心情不好  州长
I know you're upset, Governor.
要不你今天早点休息
So why don't you get a good night's sleep,
我明天一早再来
and I will come back first thing in the morning
等你状态好点我们再继续
to prep you when you're feeling better?
我把这个留在这  方便你
I'm gonna leave this for you to...
看看
look over.
美国正面临继上世纪二三十年代大萧条以来
It's the worst financial crisis facing the American people
最为严重的经济危机
since the great depression of the 1920s and '30s.
布什总统主持的大规模金融救市计划
The president's massive financial rescue plan
受到左右派的双向夹击
under fire from the left and right.
晚上好
Good evening
这里是牛津密西西比大学的福特中心
from the Ford center at the university of Mississippi at Oxford.
第一轮辩论即将开始
We're here for the first of three debates
辩手是巴拉克·奥巴马参议员
between Senator Barack Obama--
斯蒂夫  斯蒂夫  别管这些没用的形式
Steve, Steve, let's not worry about that crap.
都是狗屁
It's all bullshit.
我都站讲台上了
I'm here at the podium.
赶紧开始辩论吧
Let's do the fucking debate.
约翰  抱歉打断一下
Hey, John. Sorry to interrupt.
我刚跟财政部的人通过话
I just spoke to our guy at treasury.
投票支持议案的共和党人不够
The bill does not have enough Republican votes.
见鬼
God damn it.
保尔森认为世界经济
Paulson thinks the entire world economy
悬于一线  所以...
is on the brink of falling off the cliff, so...
咱们进退两难了   要是救市法案没通过
We're checkmated. If the bail-out doesn't pass,
我们就是被布什连累了
we're screwed because Bush,
所以你就要当替罪羊
and thus you, will be blamed for it.
如果你通过了救市法案
If you pass the bail-out--
共和党人会因为我支持
The Republicans will despise me
-救市法案而鄙视我  -没错
- for supporting a bail-out. - That's it.
没错  伙计们
This is it, guys.
他妈选举就这个德行
I mean, this is the whole fucking election.
现在  我们认为你应该暂缓竞选行程
Now, we think you should suspend the campaign,
推迟辩论  去一趟华府
postpone the debates, go to Washington,
努力谈判达成两党协议
and try to negotiate a bi-partisan compromise.
你得棋出险招了  约翰
You need to make a bold move, John.
这可是真险
This is a big risk.
赌注可不小啊
I mean, that's a big gamble.
我们必须采取行动
We gotta do something.
没什么比这事更操蛋了
I mean nothing can fuck me more than this.
州长  你有没有看过
Governor, have you had a chance
关于救市计划的材料
to go over the briefing materials on the bail-out?
我认为我们应该准备两句
I really think we need to try and nail down
简单的对于此次经济危机的评论
a simple two-sentence response to the economic crisis.
-你的评论得支持...  -粉够厚了
- It's gotta be supportive of the concept...  - That's enough powder.
救市计划的理念
...of the bail-out,
用时又要对我们目前的处境表示失望
but also disappointed that we're at this point,
明确指出法案仍需进一步修改
making it clear that changes need to be made to the bill.
你还想再高点是吗
Oh, you need it a little higher?
我会弄  我来帮你弄
I can do that. I can do that for you.
顺便说一句  你穿这件外套美极了
That jacket looks fantastic on you, by the way.
太露了
It's too open.
-你们不觉得吗  -对  非常棒
- Don't you think so - Yeah, it looks wonderful.
真的很棒  很漂亮
Really great, really nice.
颜色很好看
It's a great color.
要我给你读报纸吗
Do you want me to read the paper to you?
"约翰·麦凯恩参议员已经向他的对手
"Senator John McCain has
巴拉克·奥巴马参议员提出请求
requested of his opponent, Senator Barack Obama,
希望能推迟即将到来的辩论
a postponement of the upcoming debate
以便两位参议员能够回到国会大厦
so that both Senators may return to Capitol Hill
专注于此关键时刻的国家需求
to address the needs of the country in this crucial time.
奥巴马参议员已表示
"Senator Obama has said--"
我不喜欢这幅妆容  我不喜欢
I hate this make-up. I hate it.
我也不喜欢这发型  我喜欢全部盘起来
I don't like my hair this way. I like my hair up.
州长  你现在非常美
Governor, you look amazing.
我看上去很胖   我讨厌看起来胖
I look fat. I'm sick of looking fat.
-你一点也不胖  -能再给我点胶带吗
- You don't look fat-- - Can I get some more tape?
我不知道咱们该不该上库瑞克的节目
I don't know if we should do Couric.
她现在有些要崩溃了
She's having a mini-meltdown.
我们不能一周内麦凯恩先取消了辩论
Well, we can't have McCain cancel the debate
佩林又取消凯蒂·库瑞克的采访
and Palin cancel Katie Couric in the same week.
我知道
I know,
但是我真的很担心
but I'm really worried about her.
我说什么她都不理我
She won't respond to anything I say.
或许我们该告诉麦凯恩  看看他怎么想
Maybe we should bring McCain in and see what he thinks.
他不想掺和她的事
He doesn't want to deal with her.
我都还没告诉他  她几乎一无所知
I haven't even told him that she doesn't know anything.
你还没告诉他
You haven't told him?
听着  他不想知道
Look, he doesn't want to know.
世界经济正处于崩溃边缘
The world economy is on the brink of collapse.
你能不能  在去的路上帮她准备
Can you just... prep her in the car ride over?
我可以试试
Uh, I can try.
很好  那就试试  谢谢了
Okay, good. Try. Thanks.
以我对凯蒂的了解  她一定会问
Knowing Katie, I'm sure she's going to ask
你在女权问题上的立场
about your stance on feminism.
-你有数据吗  -什么
- Did you get the numbers? - The what?
我在阿拉斯加的支持率
My approval rating in Alaska.
还不知道
They're not in yet.
我努力去信任你们
I am trying to trust you people,
但你们却一再让我失望
but you're making it really hard for me.
很抱歉  州长
I'm sorry, Governor.
我马上给斯蒂夫打电话问清楚
I'll call Steve right away about it.
是啊  好像有济于事似的
Yeah, like that'll do anything.
你在做什么呢  州长
What are you working on, Governor?
一份来自瓦西拉"马萨谷拓荒者"报上的问卷
It's a questionnaire from the "Mat-Su Valley Frontiersman" in Wasilla.
一家阿拉斯加的报纸
You know, an Alaska paper.
你不觉得咱们应该
Don't you think we should prepare
先准备库瑞克的全国性采访吗
for your national Couric interview first?
不  妮可  不要
No, Nicolle, I don't.
这才是我的当务之急
This is my priority.
我再也不会无视阿拉斯加人民了
I am not going to ignore the people of Alaska any more.
你将阿拉斯加临近俄罗斯
You've cited Alaska's proximity to Russia
作为你外交经验的一部分
as part of your foreign policy experience.
请问这是什么意思
What did you mean by that?
阿拉斯加与俄罗斯之间仅隔着一道
That Alaska has a very narrow maritime border
非常窄的海上边界  而我们的另一边
between a foreign country, Russia, and on our other side,
又与加拿大接壤
the land boundary that we have with Canada.
可笑的是  这种评论
It's funny that a comment like that
却有意被...
was kind of made to--
我说不好  就是那些记者们
I don't know. You know, reporters.
-戏谑  -没错  戏谑
- Mocked? - Yeah, mocked.
应该就是这个词
I guess that's the word, yeah.
那请向我解释一下那为何
Well, explain to me why that enhances
能够提高你的外交能力
your foreign policy credentials.
当然可以  因为我们
Well, it certainly does because our--
我们与其它国家接壤
our next-door neighbors are foreign countries.
就在我管辖的州里
They're in the state that I am the executive of.
你是否参与过任何  比如
Have you ever been involved with any negotiations,
与俄罗斯方面的谈判
for example, with the Russians?
我们双方有贸易往来
We have trade missions back and forth.
没错  当你考虑与俄罗斯有关的
We do. It's very important
国家安全问题时  这点尤为重要
when you consider even national security issues with Russia.
普京昂首阔步进入
As Putin rears his head and comes into the airspace
美利坚合众国的领空时
of the United States of America,
他们去哪儿
where do they go?
阿拉斯加  正好紧邻着边界
It's Alaska. It's just right over the border.
说到你对世界格局的看法
And when it comes to establishing your world-view,
我想知道  在你被提名为副总统候选人前
I was curious-- what newspapers and magazines
你都读些什么报纸杂志
did you regularly read before you were tapped for this
来了解新闻讯息的
to stay informed and to understand--
大部分报纸杂志我都读  我也对
I've read most of them, again with a great appreciation
出版社和媒体持赞赏态度
for the press, for the media.
具体读些什么呢  我很好奇
What ones specifically? I'm curious.
随便说份报纸
Name one fucking paper.
都读过  任何一份
All of 'Em. Any of 'Em
曾出现在我面前的都读过
that have been in front of me over all these years.
老天  咱们到底做了什么
Oh, my God. What have we done?
如果约翰·麦凯恩赢得大选  这个女人
If John McCain wins, this woman will be
将成为72岁美国总统的
one 72-year-old's heartbeat away
第一继承人
from President of the United States.
如果你以前没觉得害怕  现在是时候了
And if that doesn't scare the hell out of you, it should.
公道点说  可能大部分人
In fairness, probably most people
都说不出一个最高法院的案子
can't name a supreme court case.
但是大部分人并没在竞选
But most people are not campaigning
-副总统  -对啊  没错
- to be vice president . - Right, right.
她不是不知道正确答案
It's not that she doesn't know the right answer.
而是压根就听不懂问题
It's that she clearly does not understand the question.
这比之前任何一位候选人
This is way beyond anything we have ever seen
所出现的任何问题都严重
from a national candidate.
你为什么让我做凯蒂·库瑞克的采访
Why'd you make me do Katie Couric?
你看到新闻报道了吗  看了吗
Did you see the coverage? Did you?
你在吗  你在听我说吗
Are you there? Are you listening to me?
是的  州长  我在听
Yes, Governor. I'm here.
凯蒂是合乎常理的选择
Katie was a logical choice.
竞选开始至今  她一直对我们不偏不倚
She's been very fair to us this entire campaign.
你认为这场采访很公平
You call that interview fair?
是的  州长  没错
Yes, Governor, I do.
我不敢苟同  她从一开始就想搞垮我
I certainly don't. She was out to get me from the get-go.
不  她没有
No, she wasn't.
采访搞砸了是因为你没努力
The interview sucked because you didn't try.
什么叫我没努力
What do you mean, I didn't try?
你没像在接受查理·吉本森采访时
You didn't fight back like you did
那样全力反击
in the Charlie Gibson interview.
当初你不知道答案时
When you didn't know the answers,
你就反问回去  效果很好
you clawed your way back and it went fine.
可是这次你却放弃了
You just gave up.
妮可  这不是我的错
Nicolle, it wasn't my fault.
是你们没帮我准备
I wasn't properly prepped.
那是因为你根本不听我们的
You weren't properly prepped because you wouldn't listen to us.
你从不听顾问们的意见
You never listen to your advisors.
因为你们一直给我灌输庞大的信息量
Because you're overwhelming me
让我喘不过气来
with too much information.
我不想接受这些采访
I don't want to do these interviews.
只想做我想做的
I want to do what I want to do.
我们在帮你克服难关  州长
We're just trying to help you get through this, Governor.
我们只期望你能赢
All we want is for you to succeed.
是吗  你们根本没在帮我
Yeah, well, you're not helping.
你们在搞垮我
You're just screwing me up.
你们告诉我该说什么  穿什么  怎么说
You're telling me what to say, what to wear, how to talk.
我不是你们的傀儡
I am not your puppet!
现在我终于明白希拉里说
Now I understand what Hillary meant
她要找到属于她自己的声音是什么意思了
when she said she had to find her own voice.
是吗  你以为你跟希拉里一样
Yeah, 'cause you're just like Hillary.
你们已经毁了我
You have ruined me.
毁了我的名誉
You have ruined my reputation.
我在阿拉斯加的名声也被毁了
I am ruined in Alaska!
我是斯蒂夫·施密特  请留言
This is Steve Schmidt. Leave a message.
斯蒂夫  我是妮可
Steve, it's Nicolle.
如果你想让我为库瑞克这件事负责我很愿意辞职
I will gladly resign if you want to blame me for Couric.
但如果你要我留下来
But if you want me to stay,
那我从明天起为麦凯恩工作
then I'm back on McCain's bus tomorrow
我再也不想管那个女人了
as I never want to deal with that woman ever again.
从伊拉克事件中你得到了什么教训
What lessons have you learned from Iraq
而你又将如何具体地在国外推进民主
and how specifically would you spread democracy abroad?
具体来说  我们将尽一切努力
Specifically, we would make every effort possible
将民主传播到需要民主的国家去
to spread democracy abroad to those who want it.
没错  请具体说说你会怎么做
Yes, but specifically , what would you do?
我们要推动自由
We're gonna promote freedom,
引入民主的价值观念与思想
usher in Democratic values and ideals,
与极端恐怖分子作斗争
and fight terror-loving terrorists.
但是  我不是想过分强调
But again, and not to belabor the point,
能说个具体举措吗
one specific thing.
凯蒂  我想打个求助电话
Katie, I'd like to use one of my lifelines.
-你说什么  -我想给一个朋友打电话
- I'm sorry? - I want to phone a friend.
周五的辩论应该照常进行
...Friday's debate should proceed.
我们时刻不停地工作
We've been working around the clock
作为国家总统就应该能同时
...and presidents are going to have to deal with
处理多件事务
more than one thing at a time.
新的CNN联合《时报》的民调显示
A new CNN/Time opinion research poll
奥巴马在若干
show Obama surging in
-摇摆州中支持率猛增  -狗娘养的
- key battleground states... - Son of a bitch.
例如他已经在宾夕尼亚州领先九个百分点
...Like Pennsylvania where he is now up by nine points.
州长  我只是想告诉你
Governor, I just want you to know
我已经得到你在阿拉斯加的民调数字
I got your Alaskan poll numbers in,
很高兴告诉你
and you'll be pleased to know
-你的支持率超过了70%  -很好
- that you're in the low 70s. - Fine.
-他们为什么这样搞我  -谁
- Why are they fucking me like this? - Who?
媒体  他们以前很喜欢我啊
The press! They used to love me.
而现在他们就靠搞垮我活着
Now all they want to do in life is fuck me over.
真不敢相信凯蒂那样对我
I can't believe Katie did that to me.
你知道昨晚奥伯曼是怎么说我的吗
And did you hear what Olbermann said about me last night?
先生  你不能再看吉斯·奥伯曼的节目
Sir, you've got to stop watching Keith Olbermann,
或福克斯台了
or FOX, for that matter.
他们都在扯淡
It's all just bullshit.
现在  先生  你应该喝杯啤酒
Now, sir, you should have a beer
24小时专门播放体育节目的有线电视联播网
看看ESPN  明白吗
and watch ESPN, okay?
并且你在看节目时
And while you're watching it,
顺便想想那些看ESPN的人
think about what the people who watch ESPN
现在最需要的是什么
really need in their lives right now.
我还以为凯蒂支持我
I thought Katie liked me.
她支持  而且这些问题也很客观公平
She does. And the questions were fair.
是佩林州长没有做好采访
It was Governor Palin who gave a terrible interview.
那可怜的姑娘
That poor girl.
她尚未做好准备
She wasn't ready for this.
是啊  恐怕你是对的  先生
Yeah, I'm afraid you're right, sir.
而且YouTube加速了事情的恶化
And YouTube is making it exponentially worse.
人们把凯蒂·库瑞克和蒂娜·费的节目
People are watching Katie Couric and Tina fey
蒂娜·费: 著名女笑星,在SNL中模仿萨拉·佩林
看了一遍又一遍
over and over again.
在网络上无限循环
It's playing like an infinite loop on the web.
以往的大选从没碰到过这种情况
No presidential campaign has ever had to deal with this before.
但她在辩论中会有好表现的  对吗
But she's gonna do a good job in the debate, right?
是的  先生  她会表现得很棒
Yes, sir. She'll be great.
因为要是库瑞克采访的那一幕重演
'Cause if it goes like Couric,
我们就再无回天之力了
I don't think we can recover.
同意  我保证她会表现得很棒的
I agree, and I promise she'll be great.
希望你是对的
I hope you're right.
我希望你是对的  斯蒂夫
I hope you're right, Steve.
一切都会好起来的
It's gonna be fine.
好了  这是96年辩论中出现的问题
Okay, this one came up in the '96 debate.
是否有解决
Is there a magic bullet
公共教育问题的灵丹妙药
to solve the problem of public education?
如果没有  最佳解决方案是什么
If not, what is the best solution?
费城
9月27日
州长
Uh, Governor?
州长  你想吃点什么吗
Governor, would you like something to eat?
没错  你是该吃点东西了  州长
Yeah, I think you should eat something, Governor.
美国著名软性饮料品牌
来一瓶无糖的胡椒博士如何
How about a diet Dr. Pepper?
你想...能不能
Would you like-- could you?
州长
Governor?
我想我的孩子了  我想和他一起睡觉
I miss my baby. I miss sleeping with my baby.
她不断陷入毫无知觉的恍惚中
She constantly slips into these catatonic stupors.
等我们好不容易让她开始工作
And then when we do finally get her to work,
她把所有东西都写在卡片上
she writes all the information down on notecards,
却一点都记不住
but she can't remember any of it.
斯蒂夫  你在阿拉斯加做过民调了吗
Steve, did you do an approval poll in Alaska?
-她一直在提这事儿  -搞毛啊
- She keeps bringing it up. - What the fuck?
我一周前做了那个该死的民调
I did that stupid fucking poll a week ago.
我告诉她支持率超过了70%
I told her she's in the 70s.
好吧  我觉得她不相信你
Yeah, well, I don't think she believes you.
她说这些数据是你瞎编的
She says you made those numbers up.
好吧
Okay.
-她越来越无理取闹了  -越来越吗
- She is becoming completely irrational. - Becoming?
我不想这样说
I don't even like to say this,
但是你们有没有想过
but has it occurred to you guys
她可能精神不稳定
that she might be mentally unstable?
马克  听着  五天后就要辩论了
Mark, look, the debate is in five days.
你有何想法
What do you think?
我认为这场辩论将是历史性的惨败
I think this debate will be a debacle of historic
前所未有的一边倒
and epic proportions.
这倒是挺鼓舞人心的
Well, that's encouraging.
你觉得让你被选为副总统候选人的
What would you say best qualifies you
最重要因素是什么
to be John McCain's running mate?
约翰·麦凯恩十分独立有主见
John McCain has that streak of independence in him
这是作为现代领袖所必须的品质
that I think is very, very important in our leadership today.
我本身也是如此
I have that within me also.
所以约翰·麦凯恩才会提名我
And that's why John McCain tapped me,
一起组成革新之队
to be a team of mavericks,
独立之队  作为这个队伍的成员
of independence as a team member
在这个  新队伍里
on this, um-- in this new team.
这个回答我要重说一遍
Um, I'm gonna do that one over again.
-好的  当然  -约翰
- Yeah, sure. - John--
州长  记住这点
Governor, important to remember
你没必要说得很具体
that you don't need to say anything specific.
明白吗  如果你不知道问题的答案
Okay? If you don't know the answer to the question,
就说回到重塑美国的主题上来
just bring it back to the general theme of reforming America
或者转移到你的强项上  比如能源
or pivot to one of your stronger suits, like energy.
好的  因为那是我最得心应手的部分
Yeah, 'cause that's where I'm most comfortable.
非常明显
That's pretty clear.
再来试试另一个问题
Let's try another question.
全球变暖
Global warming--
佩林州长  你是否相信
Governor Palin, do you believe
全球变暖是人为所致
that global warming is man-made?
我认为  这些无谓的关于全球变暖
I think all this talk and gibber-gabber
原因的无聊言论和胡言乱语完全掩盖了
about where global warming comes from defeats--
掩盖了地球越来越热的事实
defeats, you know, the point that it's getting hotter
我们都应给非常关注变暖这件事
and that we all need to be very concerned about heat.
和  呃
And, um...
那个...
That, um...
我...我...
I-- I--
不记得了  这里也没有
forgot it and it's not in this--
马克  所有卡片都该在这一摞里
Mark, all the cards are supposed to be in this pile.
-好的  - 这摞里没有
- Okay. - It's not in this pile.
大家需要休息一下
I think we need to take a break.
都出去一下好吗
Can you all leave us alone for a minute?
还有四天就是辩论会
The debate is in four days,
照此下去可不行  州长
and this isn't working, Governor.
我知道
I know.
我觉得你得赶紧扔了这些没营养的东西
I think you should get off this no-carb diet immediately.
随意节食会害了你
This goofy diet is bad for you,
你的日益消瘦让我很担心
and I'm alarmed by your weight loss.
州长  凯蒂·库瑞克的访谈没有做好
Governor, the Katie Couric interview didn't go well.
但这不是妮可·华莱士的错
And it wasn't Nicolle Wallace's fault.
不是凯蒂·库瑞克的错
It wasn't Katie Couric's fault.
也不是自由派媒体的错
It wasn't the liberal media's fault.
是你的问题  因为你准备不足
It was your fault, because you didn't prepare.
以后再也不能出现这种
And there can never be another instance
因为你没准备好而失败的事了
of something not going well because you didn't prepare.
听着  这次访谈没做好
Look, you had a bad interview.
没关系  这种事常有
It's okay, it happens.
你知道罗纳德·里根说什么是污染的源头吗
You know what Ronald Reagan said caused pollution?
树
Trees.
- 里根这么说了吗  -没错
- Reagan said that? - He did.
他说树造成了污染
He said trees cause pollution.
可他不仅在选举中获胜
And he not only won the election,
还成为了一位伟大的总统
he went on to be a great president.
只是我...我不想拖累约翰
I just-- I don't want to let John down.
斯蒂夫
Stevie boy.
我们有麻烦了
We have a problem, sir.
怎么  出什么事了
What-- what's going on?
是佩林
It's Palin.
她可能就快崩溃了
She could be on the verge of a complete nervous breakdown.
我不知道该怎么办
I don't know what to do.
我们没准备救命绳索便将她扔下深渊
We threw her into the deep end without a life preserver.
是啊  然后拖带我们走上绝路
Yeah, and we're drowning with her, sir.
我们需要让她回到家人身边
We need to get her back with her family.
她需要爱她的人
She needs to be surrounded by--
陪伴左右
by people who love her.
把他们都接去塞多纳吧
Hey, let's get 'em all out to Sedona,
呼吸呼吸新鲜空气
out in the open air.
我的邻居是个医生
My neighbor's a doctor,
辛迪可以请他来参加烧烤聚会
and Cindy can invite him over for a barbeque or something,
然后从旁观察
and he can observe her
看看佩林的情况是否严重
and see if it's truly serious.
先把他们接去塞多纳吧
But let's just get 'em to Sedona.
肯定对她大有裨益
It'll do wonders for her, I know it.
当然  没问题
Yes, sir. Absolutely.
*更加青翠的牧场*
? There be greener pastures
*就在边境的另一边*
? Cross that border line ?
*崭新的地平线*
? We'll see new horizons ?
*我的爱人*
? My darling ?
*就在峡谷的远端*
? Far beyond the great divide ?
我想死你们了
I missed you guys so much.
-妈妈  妈妈  -我的天啊
- Hi! Mommy, mommy! - Oh, my goodness!
有个小家伙也想打个招呼
Got someone who wants to say hi.
你好
Hi!
-你好  医生  -你好吗
- What's up, doc? - Hey, how you doing?
难说  她看起来怎么样
That depends. How's she look?
对于一个刚生完孩子
For a woman who's just had a baby,
未成年女儿怀有身孕
has a pregnant teen daughter
儿子远在伊拉克的女人
and a son in Iraq,
我觉得她还算不错
I'd say not half bad.
你倒是一团糟
You, however, look like shit.
他们一直告诉我一大堆东西
They keep piling all this stuff on me,
我就是没法全部都记住
and I just can't remember everything.
-总能记住其中一些吧  -是啊
- Are you getting some of it? - Yeah.
一些  可我得在台上讲90分钟
Some, but I have to talk for like 90 minutes up there.
安德鲁·海尔科 佩林竞选阿拉斯加州州长时的竞争对手
还记得你跟海尔科的那场辩论吗
Do you remember when you debated Halcro?
他没有笔记没有草稿
He had no notes, no papers,
却能一直举例论据  滔滔不绝
and he could spout off all these facts and figures?
你被吓坏了
You were so intimidated...
直到你看向观众
Until you looked out at the audience.
你意识到了什么
What'd you realize?
我意识到他说什么都无关紧要
That none of what he said mattered,
因为谁也听不懂
because no one knew what he was talking about.
现在也一样  老婆  人多一些罢了
It's the same thing here, baby. It's just more people.
你现在麻烦不断
You're getting yourself in trouble,
是因为他们想把你
because they're trying to turn you
变成一个完全不同的人
into something that you're not.
你得按自己的方式做
You gotta do what you do.
按你的方式跟观众交流
Just talk to people the way you talk to them.
他们会爱你的
And they'll love you.
他们一直都爱你
They always have.
我爱你  头号粉丝
I love you, first dude.
我也爱你
I love you, too...
副总统女士
Mrs. Vice President.
斯蒂夫  出什么事了
Steve, what's up?
这场辩论需要萨拉·佩林回答多少问题
How many questions does Sarah Palin have to answer in the debate?
22至25个
一个问题多长时间
And how long is each answer?
算上转移提问两分钟
Two minutes with pivots.
因此我们只需要让美国政坛最佳女演员
So if all we have to do is get the best actress in American politics
背下45分钟的标准答案
to memorize 45 minutes' worth of answers,
那为何浪费五天时间
then why did we waste five days
试图让她理解答案的意思呢
trying to get her to understand what any of this shit means?
州长  我没听你说要跑步啊
Governor, I didn't know you were going for a jog.
我有个新策略
I have a different strategy.
我需要让头脑清醒一点
I need to clear my head for a bit.
我们需要准备...
Well, we really need to prepare--
我真的需要跑个步  斯蒂夫
I really need to go running, Steve,
因为这样能让我好受些
'cause it's gonna make me feel better.
你能明白吗
Can you understand that?
明白  州长
Of course, Governor.
我想我们要丢掉这些卡片
I think we need to get rid of these notecards.
-它们没用  -好吧
- They're not helping. - Okay.
反正我也恨死这些卡片了
I hate those flippin' cards anyway.
现在  我们需要你
Now, what we need you to do
记住25个问题的答案和4条反问
is to memorize 25 answers and four attack lines.
你能做到吗
Do you think you can do that?
是的  我能做到
Yeah, I can do that.
那你就没问题
And you're gonna be great.
正如里根总统所说
And we are to be that shining city on a hill,
我们将成为顶峰最闪亮的城市
as President Reagan so beautifully said,
我们是希望的灯塔
and that we are a beacon of hope
不需要向任何人解释我们的存在
and that we are unapologetic here.
佩林州长
Governor Palin,
伊朗核项目是我们最大的威胁之一
nuclear Iran is one of our gravest threats.
麦凯恩政府会采取什么制裁措施
What would a McCain administration do to stop it?
在伊朗核问题上
On the subject of "nucular" Iran,
我基本赞成参议员奥拜登的观点
Senator O'Biden and I are most likely in agreement.
决不允许他们拥有任何核武器
They cannot be allowed to acquire "nucular" weapons, period.
当然  在同伊朗总统内贾德的较量中
Israel is in jeopardy, of course,
以色列目前处于劣势
when dealing with Ahmadi Nejad as a leader of Iran.
罗纳德·里根曾说过  自由的延续与毁灭
It was Ronald Reagan who said that freedom
就看一代人的选择
is always just one generation away from extinction.
自由不是血脉相传的
We don't pass it to our children in the bloodstream,
而需要我们去争取  去捍卫
we have to fight for it and protect it,
将其亲手交与后辈
and then hand it to them
他们才能同样争取捍卫自由
so that they shall do the same.
我们会为之奋斗
We will fight for it.
而这场选举中  唯有一人
And there is only one man in this race
曾真正为你们争取过自由
who has really ever fought for you,
那就是参议员约翰·麦凯恩
and that's Senator John McCain.
真棒
Yeah!
太好了 她找回状态了
Yeah, she's back!
萨拉·佩林回归了  女士们先生们
Sarah Palin is back, ladies and gentlemen.
-干得漂亮  州长  -还不错吧
- Great job, Governor. - It was pretty good, huh?
岂止不错  简直一级棒
Pretty good? It was amazing.
只有一个小错误需要纠正
There's just one slight adjustment I want to give you.
你应该叫他参议员拜登
You need to call him Senator Biden,
而不是参议员奥拜登
not Senator O'Biden.
我是这么说的  参议员奥拜登
That's what I called him, Senator O'Biden.
-你又错了  -哪里错了
- You just said it again. - Said what?
-奥拜登  -对  参议员拜登
- O'Biden. - Right. Senator Biden.
-对了  -噢  拜登
- That's it. - Oh. Biden.
不  没有奥
No, no, there's no "O."
这是"噢 我懂了"的"噢"
No, I meant "Oh," As in "Oh, I get it,"
不是奥拜登的"奥"
not "O" As in O'Biden.
好吧  我们练练
Okay, well, let's practice it.
州长  你赞成参议员拜登
Governor, do you agree with Senator Biden's
在救市计划上的立场吗
position on the bail-out?
-参议员奥拜登...  -拜登
- Senator O'Biden-- - Biden!
真该死
Doggone it!
-我是萨拉  -是我  妈妈
- This is Sarah. - Hey, mom.
乖儿子  你还好吗
Hey, honey. How are ya?
我很好  我...
I'm good. I'm--
-我很好  妈妈  -你在哪儿呢
- I'm good, mom. - Where are you?
这个我不能透露
Um, I'm not really allowed to say.
好吧  宝贝  不过你是安全的吧
Okay, sweetie, but you're safe?
是啊  别担心  我很安全
Yeah, no, I'm fine, I'm fine.
我只是想祝你辩论顺利
I just wanted to wish you a good debate.
谢谢
Thank you.
-你有学习吗  -有
- Did you study? - I did.
很用功
A lot.
我会为你祈祷的
I'll be praying for you.
太好了  我正需要
Please, I'll need it.
加油  妈妈  你能搞定它的
Come on, mom, you're gonna do great.
我爱你
I love you.
我也非常爱你  特拉克
I love you so much, Track.
-集合  -我得挂了  妈妈
- Fall in! - I gotta go, mom.
别别别  再等一分钟
No, no, no. Just-- just another minute.
抱歉  我真的得走了
No, I'm really sorry, but I really gotta go.
你今晚会表现出色的  知道吗
You're gonna do great tonight, okay?
谢谢宝贝  你千万要注意安全
Thank you, thank you, but, sweetie-- sweetie, you be safe.
我会的
I will.
再见
Bye.
你还好吧
You okay?
我儿子很安全
My son is safe.
我们即将看到的
Well, what we are going to see
将是我所报道过的
is probably the most anticipated
最令人期待的副总统辩论
vice presidential debate that I have covered ever.
华盛顿大学
圣路易斯
萨拉·佩林承受着巨大压力
A lot, a lot of pressure on Sarah Palin.
10月2日
而对乔·拜登来讲
As for Joe Biden, it's sort of a,
今晚不必有所顾忌
first of all, do-no-harm night for him.
至少没有人会质疑
No one has questioned
他当副总统的资格
that he is qualified to be vice president.
他需要...他们都需要
He needs to-- both of them,
需要重点谈论各自的总统候选人
need to talk about the top of their tickets.
毕竟  这场选举不是在选副总统
After all, this isn't a race to be vice president
所以在选票事宜上
so much as it is to be number two
他们只是二号人物
to the top people on the ticket.
在乔·拜登方面  你肯定会听到
On the Joe Biden side, you will see
他强调  "瞧  萨拉·佩林..."
an effort to say, "Look, Sarah Palin..."
快点
Hurry.
我们一起祈祷
Pray with me.
祈祷什么呢
What should we pray for?
祈祷我们能赢了这场辩论
Just pray that we win the debate.
妈妈  这可是作弊
Mom, that would be cheating.
好了
Okay.
欢迎全美以及全球的观众
We want to welcome our viewers
收看我们的节目
in the United States and around the world.
我是沃尔夫·布利泽  同最优秀的...
I'm Wolf Blitzer, together with the best...
今晚我们期待已久的...
We've been waiting for this night for a long time...
杰罗丁·费拉罗  民主党人  美国第一位参选副总统的女性
1984年  杰拉德琳·费拉罗也是由我带进场的
I did this same walk for Geraldine Ferraro in 1984.
天啊  那可真棒
Holy jeez, that's cool.
你就站在这里
This is your toe mark.
好的
Okay.
30秒准备
2号机  镜头拉回广角拍她进场
Two, pull back wide on her entrance, please.
2号机准备  2号机切入
Ready, two. And take two.
晚上好  这里是密苏里州圣路易斯的
Good evening from Washington University
华盛顿大学
in St. Louis, Missouri.
我是来自PBS《新闻一小时》
I'm Gwen Ifill of the "News Hour"
和《华盛顿周讯》的格温·艾菲尔
and "Washington Week" on PBS.
欢迎收看2008年独一无二的
Welcome to the first and the only 2008
副总统辩论会
vice presidential debate
辩论在共和党提名人
between the Republican nominee,
阿拉斯加州州长萨拉·佩林
Governor Sarah Palin of Alaska,
和民主党提名人
and the Democratic nominee,
德拉维尔州参议员乔·拜登间举行
Joe Biden of Delaware.
今晚的议题涵盖范围相当广泛
Tonight's discussion will cover a wide range of topics,
包括国内政策和对外政策
including domestic and foreign policy matters.
每位候选人将有90秒时间
Each candidate will have 90 seconds
回答一个直接提问
to respond to a direct question
以及额外两分钟
and then an additional two minutes
进行抗辩和追叙
for rebuttal and follow-up.
具体主题以及问题都由我亲自选择
The specific subjects and questions were chosen by me
并未向双方阵营和选举委员会
and have not been shared or cleared
透露也未经他们批准
with anyone on the campaigns or on the commission.
现场观众已保证
The audience here in the hall
将在整场辩论中保持安静
has promised to remain very polite--
不欢呼  不鼓掌  不制造无故动静
no cheers, applause, no untoward outbursts...
-拜登  拜登...   -现在
- Biden. Biden. Biden. - ...Except right at this minute
让我们欢迎州长佩林和参议员拜登
as we welcome Governor Palin and senator Biden.
幸会  我能叫你乔吗
Nice to meet you. Hey, can I call you Joe?
当然可以
You can call me Joe.
-为...为什么麦克开着  -没事  不要紧
- Why-- why is the mic on? - No, no, no, it's cool.
他们会把这看作是
They're gonna think it's some kind
马基亚维利: 意大利政治思想家, 注重军事
马基亚维利和绝地武士的较量
of Machiavellian Jedi power-play.
听你说这种话...斯蒂夫
From your lips, Steve.
欢迎二位
Welcome to you both.
本周国会众议院通过了一项议案
The House of Representatives this week passed a bill,
2008年10月美国通过了7000亿美元救市计划
拟从陷于困境的金融企业买入问题资产
救市法案
a big bail-out bill--
或者说没有通过
or didn't pass it, I should say.
参议院决定通过
The Senate decided to pass it
众议院直至今晚仍未作出表决
and the House is wrestling with it still tonight.
这究竟是政府的英明之举
Was this the worst of Washington or the best of Washington
还是大胆拙计呢
that we saw play out?
感谢你   格温  也感谢选举委员会
Thank you, Gwen, and I thank the commission also.
能有幸在此同全美人民对话
I appreciate this privilege of being able to be here
我很感激
and speak with Americans.
上帝保佑啊
Please, God, be kind.
我认为  在我们试图评判
You know, I think a good barometer here
此时对美国经济是好是坏时
when we're trying to figure out has this been a good time
最好的标准就是
or a bad time in America's economy is...
周六去看场儿童足球赛
go to a kids' soccer game on Saturday
转身随便问个场外的家长
and turn to any parent there on the sideline and ask them,
"你觉得现在经济状况如何"
"How are you feeling about the economy?"
我敢保证你能从他的回答中
And I'll betcha you're gonna hear
听出一丝恐惧
some fear in that parent's voice...
她做得不错啊
She's doing great.
我们还有88分钟呢
We've got 88 more minutes.
我们的投资是不是都打了水漂了
Did we just take a major hit with those investments?
是要谈到人类活动对气候的影响
There is something to be said also for man's activities,
但也要考虑到地球周期性温度变化的因素
but also for the cyclical temperature changes on our planet.
参议员  这些原因中孰是孰非
Senator, what is true and what is false about the causes?
如果不清楚问题的源泉
If you don't understand what the cause is,
就无法采取正确的措施
it's virtually impossible to come up with a solution.
现在的口号是"钻啊钻井打石油"
The chant is "Drill, baby, drill."
不管我们在哪举行集会
And that's what we hear all across this country
都能听见大家高喊口号
in our rallies, because people are so hungry
渴望这些国内能源
for those domestic sources of energy
能被更加充分地利用
to be tapped into.
我们会结束这场战争
We will end this war.
若麦凯恩当选
For John McCain,
战争会无休无止
there is no end in sight to end this war.
而我们会结束这场战争
We will end this war.
州长女士
Governor...
你的计划
Your plan
无疑是要让我们在伊拉克
is a white flag of surrender
-缴械投降  -太棒了
- in Iraq. - Yes!
州长  请问您对于麦凯恩参议员
Governor, please, did you want to respond
就医保的回答  有何回应
to Senator McCain's comments about healthcare?
转移话题  快
Pivot. Pivot!
我想就提高税收这一问题进行回应
I'd like to respond about the tax increases and...
这就对了
Yes!
我们要增加就业
Darn right, we need tax relief
当然要减轻美国民众的税收负担
for Americans so that jobs can be created here.
巴拉克·奥巴马和奥拜登参议员
Barack Obama and Senator O'Biden,
你们什么都不认可
you said no to everything...
她刚说了奥拜登
She just said O'Biden.
大概只有我们注意到了
We're probably the only ones that heard it.
罗纳德·里根曾说过  自由的延续与毁灭
It was Ronald Reagan who said that freedom
就看一代人的选择
is always just one generation away from extinction.
自由不是血脉相传的
We don't pass it to our children in the bloodstream.
而需要我们去争取  去捍卫
We have to fight for it and protect it,
将其亲手交与后辈
and then hand it to them
他们才能同样争取捍卫自由
so that they will do the same.
我们会为之奋斗
We will fight for it.
而这场选举中  唯有一人
And there is only one man in this race
曾真正为你们争取过自由
who has really ever fought for you,
那就是参议员约翰·麦凯恩
and that's Senator John McCain.
好  来了
Okay, here we go.
哥伦比亚广播公司快速民意调查显示
CBS instant poll says undecideds
46%调查对象认为拜登赢  佩林21%
give the debate to Biden, 46%; Palin, 21.
甭管他们那个破调查
Fuck CBS and fuck their instant poll.
这是共和党有史以来
This is the greatest debate victory
最成功的辩论了
in the history of the Republic.
你看  只要做你自己就好了
You see? You just had to be you.
我去拿杯啤酒
I'm gonna grab a beer.
-你要吗  -不用
- Want one? - No.
参议员麦凯恩让我转达他对你的祝贺
Senator McCain wanted me to congratulate you
辩论很成功
on a fantastic debate.
-讲得非常棒  -谢谢
- You really did a great job. - Thanks.
奥巴马 瑞特牧师风波及亲近恐怖分子比尔·埃尔斯事件
告诉他我想谈谈比尔·埃尔斯和瑞特牧师
Tell John I want to bring up Bill Ayers and Reverend Wright.
我觉得是时候锁喉一击了
I think it's time to go for the jugular.
这个得和竞选伙伴商量
You'll have to discuss that with your running mate.
他明确地表示不想提到瑞特事件
He made it very clear that he doesn't want to touch Wright.
我会跟他说的
I'll talk to him about it.
我们必须取胜
We have to win this thing.
我不想再回阿拉斯加了
I so don't want to go back to Alaska.
斯蒂夫
Stevie.
我觉得最糟的已经过去了
You know, I think the worst of this thing might be over.
剩下的都是演讲了
All she's got left are speeches.
没有辩论  也没有重要的采访了
There's no more debates, no major interviews.
是  情形不错
Yeah. We're doing great.
莎拉·佩林不可思议地大获全胜
This was an unbelievable win for Sarah Palin.
我认为  她高超的演说和沟通能力
In fact, I think that it unveiled a level of skill
自罗纳德·里根之后
in communication that I really have not seen
无人可及
since Ronald Reagan.
她是个超级明星
She is a superstar.
她的能力...
Her ability to by...
她无疑是政坛的一缕清风
And she sure is a breath of fresh air.
我认为民众想要个
I mean, I think people want
华盛顿政治圈外的人
someone from outside of Washington.
她代表着未来
She sounded like the future.
睡吧  宝贝
Come on, honey.
早点休息吧
Why don't you get some sleep?
就一会  好吗
One sec, okay?
逆转了局势  她做到了
...Turned around. I think she has done it
且在我看来  4位辩手中
in the sense that of the four debaters we've seen,
她最有意思  最吸引人
she was the most interesting, attractive of them all.
-她很平易近人...  -还是有胜算的
- She is personable... - I can still win this thing.
...她很有幽默感
...She's got a sense of humor.
乔一直只对着格温说话
She looked straight into the camera
她却直视镜头
while Joe's talking to Gwen...
投票局势现倾向于奥巴马
This map is now lopsided in favor of Barack Obama.
270票之争  奥巴马250  麦凯恩189
约翰·麦凯恩放弃了密西根
John McCain pulling out of Michigan.
走向经济竞选的第一步
The first domino in an economic debate
而若约翰·麦凯恩再不扭转局势
that if John McCain does not turn around soon,
这张图上会有更多蓝色
we may see more blue on this map
而约翰·麦凯恩也就麻烦大了
and more trouble for John McCain.
昨天竞选团队宣称放弃密西根
Yesterday, it was announced that the campaign
把该州选票拱手让给奥巴马
is going to leave Michigan to Obama to win.
-解释一下怎么回事  -我也今早才得知
- What's going on there? - I read that this morning also,
我立马就发了邮件
and I fired off a quick e-mail
说  "拜托  不退出不行吗"
and I said, "Oh, come on! Do we have to?"
"我们真得放弃吗"
"Do we have to call it there?"
我想回到密西根  我想尽力一试
I want to go back to Michigan, and I want to try.
怎么回事
What the fuck?
麦凯恩本来只打算路过拉几张票
McCain had hoped to just score a pick-up.
我们决定停止密西根州的竞选宣传
We made the decision to pull the ads out of Michigan
因为那里没有胜算
because we can't win there.
我们需要把钱投入到宾州和俄亥俄州
We need the money in Pennsylvania and Ohio.
你这是大错特错了
You're making a big mistake.
虽说我不是专家
You know, I know I'm not an expert like yourself,
但既然我们落后了7个百分点
but seeing as we're seven points out,
我不明白为什么副总统竞选
I don't see why the vice presidential campaign
半夜路过密西根时
can't make a quick stop there
不能顺道造访一下
in the middle of the night.
那你打算去见谁
And who are you gonna meet with?
你的新闻团队
Your press corps doesn't want
不会半夜3点听你演讲的
to hear you speak at 3:00 in the morning.
再说也没有什么副总统竞选
And there's no such thing as a vice presidential campaign.
只有约翰·麦凯恩的总统竞选
This is John McCain's campaign,
而决定也是约翰·麦凯恩做的
and this is the decision that John McCain has made.
你得按计划来  州长
You must stick to the script, Governor.
什么计划  斯蒂夫
And what script is that, Steve?
我从加盟你们这竞选团队来
'Cause I haven't seen anything resembling
就没看到过什么计划
a script this entire flippin' campaign.
对麦凯恩不利
你公开反驳约翰·麦凯恩
When you publicly contradict John McCain,
会有害于他的竞选
you hurt John McCain.
我知道我知道些什么
I know what I know what I know.
看见了吧
And there you have it.
午安  州长
Afternoon, Governor.
这广告是支持干细胞研究的
This is a pro-stem cell ad?
是的州长  参议员支持干细胞研究
Yes, Governor. That's the Senator's position.
但我不支持  我不说
Yeah, it's not my position. I'm not saying it.
我以为
I thought that...
你们该把剧本提前给我
You guys should have shown me the script ahead of time.
真是浪费生命
This is a waste of my time.
为什么没有人告诉我
Why wasn't I informed that Jeb Bradley
杰博·布拉德利会和我一同出席集会
is appearing with me at the rally?
我们没觉得这是个问题
I don't think we foresaw that being a problem.
我查了下  他支持堕胎
I just googled him. He's pro-choice.
我绝不和支持堕胎的人站在一起
There's no way I'm going onstage with anyone who's pro-choice.
有他没我  没商量
Bradley's gone or I'm gone, period.
是的  州长
Yes, Governor.
联邦选举委员会报告指出
The RNC spent a stunning $150,000
共和党花费了15万美元
on clothes for Governor Sarah Palin and her family
为州长莎拉·佩林及家人购置服装
according to the Federal Election Commission reports.
在诸如内曼·马库斯
The revelation that so much money
奢侈高端精品百货店
和萨克斯第五大道精品百货店
was spent at fancy clothing stores
等高档服饰店一掷千金
like Neiman Marcus and Saks Fifth Avenue
无疑会严重损害州长
could be a huge blow to the Governor's image
共和党花费15万元为莎拉·佩林置装
平易近人的形象
as an everyday, average American.
共和党几位赞助者
Several Republican donors
已经公开的表达了愤慨
have publicly expressed outrage...
-你看了吗  -是  在看
- You watching this? - Yeah, I'm watching.
太他妈的难以置信了
Un-fucking-believable.
你们为什么不告诉我
Why didn't you people tell me
这些衣服这么贵
these clothes cost this much?
不只是你的衣服  州长
It wasn't just your clothes, Governor.
还有孩子们的  托德和你父母的
It was also for the kids, Todd and your parents.
都拿走
I want 'em gone.
我不想要
Get 'em out of here.
我都是在寄卖店买衣服的
You know, I buy my clothes at consignment shops.
我从来也不想要这些花里胡哨的衣服
I never wanted this fancy crap in the first place.
你好  很感谢你能来
Hey, thanks for coming out.
你好  你好  很高兴见到你
Hey. Hi, nice to meet you.
-你怎么样  你好啊  -佩林州长
- How are you? Hey, hi. - Governor Palin,
阿拉斯加州议会报告
what's your response to the findings
指出你参与州警们事件
that the Alaska state legislature's report
你对此作何回应
on your involvement in the Troopergate scandal?
我很高兴那份报告能还我清白
I was thrilled to be cleared of all wrongdoing.
你不该在这里
You know you're not supposed to be here.
请回到记者席  谢谢
Go back to the press risers, please. Thank you.
你不能说报告还你清白了
You can't say you were cleared of all wrongdoing.
-为什么  -因为它没有
- Why not? - Because you weren't.
那份报告说你滥用职权
The report stated that you abused your power.
和还你清白正相反
That is the opposite of being cleared of all wrongdoing.
那为什么别人说我清白了
Then why was I told otherwise?
没人这么告诉你
You weren't told otherwise.
你们怎么还不发表声明
And why haven't you released a statement
托德从来不是
saying that Todd was never a member
阿拉斯加独立党成员
of the Alaska Independence Party?
因为那不是事实  他是独立党成员
Because that would be untrue. He was a member.
他选错选项了
He checked the wrong box.
他无意中注册的
He registered by accident,
并立马改正了错误
and rectified the error immediately.
他注册独立党7年了
He was a member for seven years!
抱歉  州长  但是...
I'm sorry, Governor, but...
竞选已经接近尾声了
There is only a few weeks left in this campaign.
这几星期内  你不能再这么
You have got to stop saying things to the press
公开欺骗媒体了
that are blatantly untrue.
我们的竞选不能像这样下去
That is not the kind of campaign that we are running here.
"竞选"  你管这个叫竞选吗
"Campaign", is that what you're calling this now?
州长  我知道这个竞选团运作有点混乱
Governor, I admit that this is a dysfunctional campaign,
但我接手时就是这样
but that is what I inherited,
而我正在尽全力帮我们赢得竞选
and I am doing my level best to help us win this election.
我也在尽力  斯蒂夫
And that's what I'm trying to do, too, Steve
而你就是在拖我后腿
and all you're doing is screwing me up.
你一直以来就是给我捣乱
That's all you've done this entire time, is get in my way.
而且我给这个竞选筹得了几百万的资金
And I am raising millions of dollars for this campaign.
上千万的人赶来
Hundreds of thousands of people are coming
看我演讲的  而不是看约翰·麦凯恩
to see me speak, not John McCain, God bless him.
他们是来看我的
They are coming to see me.
既然是我撑起了这个"竞选"
So if I am single-handedly carrying this "campaign",
我想做什么就做什么
I'm gonna do what I want.
莎拉  莎拉
Sarah! Sarah! Sarah!
麦凯恩团队几位顾问向CNN透露说
Several McCain advisors tell CNN they're annoyed
他们对"不受约束的佩林"感到很反感
by what one aide called "Palin going rogue."
该死的
God damn it.
竞选没结束就有泄密和恶意中伤了
I hate it when there's leaking and backstabbing
结束后的中伤我都恨之入骨呢
after a campaign, let alone before it's fucking over.
你得出面去跟她谈谈
I need you to step in and talk to her.
算了吧  斯蒂夫
I don't know, Stevie boy. I don't know.
先生
Sir...
我控制不了她了
I can't control her any more.
我都不知道她早上是否有心情上飞机
I don't know if she's getting on a campaign plane
也不知道她晚上讲话会说什么
in the morning or what she's gonna say at night.
我们得以尽可能高雅的姿态
We need to finish this campaign
完成整个竞选
with as much dignity as possible,
我们要做到这一点
and the only way that can happen
就得让她守规矩
is if you get her in line.
我说也没用  斯蒂夫
That's not gonna do it, Steve.
她可能会直接跟我对着干
She might start turning on me.
大部分民意调查指出我们落后
Most of these polls have us trailing
5到8个百分点
five to eight points.
-那现在怎么办  -约翰
- So what now? - John...
这些数字很明显了
I mean, these numbers do show it.
我们得开始针对奥巴马了
We've got to make this about Obama.
得开始攻击他
We've got to get tough
开始负面竞选了
and we've got to get negative.
如果这样
If we go this way,
瑞特牧师是我们手上最好的牌了
Reverend Wright is still the best play we have.
你们谁被指控过
Any of you ever been accused
麦凯恩最小的女儿布里吉特领养自孟加拉国
你的黑鬼孩子是私生女吗
of having a negro child out of wedlock
就因为你的养女是孟加拉裔
because your adopted daughter was born in Bangladesh?
在她16岁时
And then when she was 16
在谷歌上搜了自己的名字  我得给她解释
and googled her name, I had to explain to her
为什么她10岁的时候  布什总统的二把手
why President Bush's henchmen called her a bastard
就骂她是私生子
when she was 10 years old.
听我说  南卡州的初选是挺恶心的
Yeah, listen, South Carolina-- that was an ugly primary,
但这不是一码事
but this isn't the same thing.
瑞特牧师的确说了那些话
I mean, Reverend Wright really did say those things.
那也许是事实
That may be true.
但美国民众心里也有阴暗面
But there is a dark side to American populism.
有些人靠伎俩赢得选举
Some people win elections by tapping into it.
我不会这么做
I'm not one of those people.
好吧  比尔·埃尔斯怎么样
Okay. So what about Bill Ayers?
奥巴马的政途
Obama began his career
始于国内恐怖分子的起居室
in the living room of a domestic terrorist.
国内恐怖分子  和种族无关
Domestic terrorist. Nothing to do with race.
好吧
Yeah, okay.
埃尔斯可以用
Ayers is fair.
好吧  谁来说
Okay. Who should do this?
巴拉克政途的首次会议
And Barack held one of the first meetings
是在比尔·埃尔斯的起居室开的
of his political career in Bill Ayers' living room.
和恐怖分子打成一团
Pallin' around with terrorists.
他不是基督徒
He's not a Christian!
我很忧心
And I am just so fearful
这一位候选人
that this is not a man
对美国的看法
who sees America
与你我都不同
the way that you and I see America...
他搞共产主义
He's a socialist!
而我们把美国看做世界上善良的源泉
...as the greatest source for good in this world.
美利坚  美利坚
U.S.A.! U.S.A.!
U.S.A.! U.S.A.! U.S.A.!
巴拉克·奥巴马为美国做了什么打算
What does Barack Obama plan for America?
我们要一个真正的美国人做总统
没有
Nothing!
总结下  奥巴马到底是什么人
In short, who is the real Barack Obama?
恐怖分子
A terrorist!
我们相信  美国的精英
We believe that the best of America
不全在华盛顿  我们相信
is not all in Washington, D. C. We believe--
我们相信美国的精髓
we believe that the best of America
正是在我们到的这些小镇里
is in these small towns that we get to visit
这些美丽的小地方
and in these wonderful little pockets
才是真正的美国
of what I call the real America.
说得好
Yes!
萨拉  萨拉
Sarah! Sarah!
作为写了两本传记的人
For a man who's written two memoirs,
他可不是那么好看懂的
he's no open book.
这你可说对了
You got that right.
巴拉克·奥巴马想为美国做什么
What does Barack Obama see for America?
他是个穆斯林
He's a Muslim!
他搞社会主义
He's a socialist!
-他不能代表我们  -他不属于这里
- He doesn't represent us! - He doesn't belong here!
他和痛恨我们国家的人在一起混
He hangs out with people who hate our country.
-他不是美国人  -杀了他
- He's not American! - Kill him!
把他赶回非洲去
Send him back to Africa!
塔拉  我给你读一下
Let me read to you, Tara,
约翰·路易斯众议员  民权偶像人物
what Congressman John Lewis, the civil rights icon,
在周六发表的声明
said on Saturday in a statement.
他说  作为一位在民权运动高峰
He said, "As one who was a victim of violence"
历经暴力与憎恨的人
and hate during the height of the civil rights movement,
我很担忧目前来自麦凯恩-佩林阵营
I am deeply disturbed by the negative tone
的负面声音
of the McCain-Palin campaign.
麦凯恩参议员与佩林州长
Senator McCain and Governor Palin"...
我们不能再这么骂他了
We gotta tone the rhetoric down.
要失去控制了
It's gotten out of control.
我们都不能提奥巴马的名字了
We can't even mention Obama's name any more.
不然要群情激奋了
The crowd gets too hot.
我不想这样竞选
This isn't the campaign I wanted to run.
我无法相信奥巴马
I can't trust Obama.
我读过关于他的事  他不是...
I've read about him, and he's not a--
他是...他是阿拉伯人
he's a-- he's an Arab.
他都算不上美国...
He's not an Amer--
不  您错了
No, Ma'am.
您说错了
他是有家庭的正直的男人
He's a decent family-man citizen
我与他不过是在一些方面
who I just happen to have disagreements with
政见不合而已
on certain fundamental issues.
此次竞选也正是为此  并无其他
And that's what this campaign is all about.
他是个好人  谢谢您
He's not. Thank you.
从今晚的大好局势来看
Cutting through the bull tonight,
凤凰城
11月3日
在大选前夕
on the eve of the election,
双方都在赌自己的运气
the campaigns are relying on their lucky charms.
来杯加冰的伏特加  配莱姆汁
Vodka rocks, lime.
稍等  这就好
You got it.
他还好吗
How's he doing?
自竞选以来  我从没看到他如此沮丧过
He's the most depressed I've seen him the entire campaign.
我都没法让他别看MSNBC
I can't get him to stop watching MSNBC,
他越看心里越不爽
which only makes him more miserable.
我很惊讶他这样的政坛老手
I'm amazed that someone who has been in politics
也会把这些琐碎的小事
this long takes all the petty stuff
放在心上
so personally.
也正是这种性格成就了他们
And that's why they are who they are.
里根  布什  克林顿  都是如此
that's Reagan, Bush, Clinton--
他们期望讨所有人的欢心
all they want is to be loved.
对于民众的爱无欲无求的人
The ones that don't pathologically need to be loved,
无法成为总统候选人
they don't get the nomination.
也无法成为总统
They don't get to be President.
你要是早知道这点
If you'd understood that fact,
说不定你就有本事
you might have been able
驾驭这位阿拉斯加的麋鹿猎手
to better handle our Alaskan moose hunter.
我的天  这真是一场艰难的竞选
God, it was a tough campaign.
这不是竞选  这是一场糟糕的真人秀
It wasn't a campaign, it was a bad reality show.
她并没有拉低我们的选票
She didn't cost us the election.
布什  经济状况  这些才是问题关键
That was Bush. That was the economy.
命数已定
That was just the cold hand of fate.
我们已经没有机会了
We didn't have a chance.
如果我们胜选的话
And if we did win,
你能接受佩林总统么
would you feel comfortable with President Palin?
当然可以  要能接受不就赢了
Why not? Then we would have won.
听着  伙计们
Come on, guys, listen.
我也希望美国公民能够选出下一位
I, too, wish that the American people
阿伯拉罕·林肯或
would choose the future Abraham Lincoln
下一位托马斯·杰弗逊  可不幸的是
or Thomas Jefferson, but unfortunately,
游戏规则已经变了
that's not the way it works any more.
你现在得靠自己的
Now it takes movie star charisma
明星光环来赢得竞选
to get elected president.
奥巴马和佩林  他们就是明星
And Obama and Palin, that's what they are-- they're stars.
而他们的根本区别在于
Primary difference being
萨拉·佩林连个高等法院案例都说不出来
Sarah Palin can't name a supreme court decision,
而巴拉克·奥巴马
whereas Barack Obama
曾经是一位宪法教授
was a constitutional law Professor.
你去死吧
Fuck you.
你知道切尼那家伙知道
You know what Dick Cheney said
-我们选了她以后说啥了吗  -什么
- when he found out we picked her? - What?
他说我们太不计后果了
He said we made a reckless choice.
如果连切尼都开始觉得你有问题的话
When you lose the moral high ground to Dick Cheney,
你真该好好反思人生了
it's time to re-think your entire life.
别再提切尼了行吗
Enough Cheney cracks, okay?
大家一直都误解他
I mean, he's very misunderstood.
我一直很费解
How does he eat when he's wearing
他怎么戴着黑武士的头盔吃东西呢
Darth Vader's helmet, anyway?
这样才对嘛
There we go.
伙计们  让我们祝彼此好运吧
Gentlemen, let's wish each other good luck.
天知道我们是不是要应对一场
Who knows, we could have another
杜威对垒杜鲁门式的竞选呢
Dewey-Truman situation here.
在1948年的美国总统大选中  杜鲁门以微弱优势险胜杜威
要郁闷以后有的是时间
Always room for an upset.
是啊  没准明早我会长出满头黑发
Yeah, maybe I'll wake up with a full head of hair.
如果我们一开始问了她政策问题的话
You know, if we had just asked for policy questions
我们就能心里有数
in the briefing, then we would have known.
我以为库尔华豪斯会刁难她呢
I thought Culvahouse was gonna grill her during the vet.
库尔华豪斯还以为我们会刁难她呢
Culvahouse thought we were gonna grill her.
我非常纠结
It haunts me.
在一场艰难的对垒之后
After a hard-fought battle,
有史以来持续时间最长的一次总统竞选
the nation's longest-running presidential race
将在今天落下帷幕  选举日终于到来
comes down to this day-- election day.
投票已经在48个州正式全面展开
Voting is now underway in all the lower 48 states
这场历史性选举的胜负即将见分晓
as we approach the end of this historic election.
数百万的美国人今天都走上了街头
People lined up across the country
排队等着投票
by the millions today.
这是近几十年来参与投票人数最多的一次
Turnout looks to be the highest in decades.
约翰·麦凯恩如期拿下了肯塔基州
John McCain will carry Kentucky once again, as expected.
共八张选举人票  我们对此并不意外
Eight electoral votes, not a huge surprise.
截止到目前为止  还有另外四个州的
We are not able to make a projection
投票已经全部结束
in the four other states...
但是我们还无法对这四个州的
that are closing all their polls
投票结果做出预测
at this hour right now.
这几个州也是竞选过程中竞争最为激烈的
And some of them are battleground states--
佐治亚州  印第安纳州
Georgia, Indiana,
南卡莱罗纳州和弗吉尼亚州
South Carolina and Virginia.
当然这并不意味选情会很胶着
It doesn't necessarily mean that it's gonna be close or not...
弗吉尼亚州情况如何
Where's Virginia?
落后五个点  俄亥俄州已经失选了
Negative five. And Ohio's gone.
-明白  -我会随时汇报给你
- Got it. - I'll keep you posted.
我过十分钟再打给你
Call you in 10.
怎么了
What's going on?
宾州要失选了
We're gonna lose Pennsylvania.
俄亥俄州也是
And Ohio.
斯蒂夫
Steve...
有件事我必须告诉你
There's something I have to tell you.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我没投票
I didn't vote.
我做不到
I couldn't do it.
我没有投票
I didn't vote.
我真的做不到
I couldn't do it.
没关系
It's okay.
-孤独啊  -好的  我们接下来
- Soledad. - All right, wolf,
马上进行选民分析
we'll take you right to the voter analysis...
情况怎么样 斯蒂夫
How we doing, Stevie boy?
宾州和俄亥俄州已经失选了
We lost Pennsylvania and Ohio, sir.
当年我的祖父在听说日本已经投降之后
When my grandfather found out that the Japanese had surrendered,
他不知所措
he was lost.
他不知道自己接下来该怎么办
He didn't know what to do with himself.
他回到家里
He came home,
第二天便暴毙而亡
dropped dead the very next day.
全力战斗  慷慨赴死
Fought his war, then he died.
我的父亲
And my dad,
自他从海军退役后
when he retired from the Navy,
就陷入了深深的绝望
he fell into a sense of despair for the rest of his life.
我是不会放弃的  斯蒂夫
I'm never gonna quit, Steve.
我不能放弃
I can't.
我不知道应该怎样淡出政坛
I don't know how to just fade away.
参议员  我...
Senator, I--
我只想告诉您...
I just want to say--
什么
What?
我...我...
I'm s-- I'm s--
我真的非常抱歉
I'm so sorry that I...
我举荐了她
suggested her.
不用愧疚
Don't be.
去他们的吧
Fuck 'em.
我们还能怎么办呢
What were we supposed to do?
今夜对于整个美国来说具有历史性的意义
A truly historic night here in the United States.
巴拉克·奥巴马
Barack Obama will become
将成为美国的第44任总统
the 44th President of the United States.
我很遗憾  妈妈
Sorry, mom.
谢谢你  孩子
Oh, thanks, kiddo.
我真的非常遗憾  妈妈
I'm really sorry, mom.
亲爱的
Sweetheart.
你知道吗  你真的棒极了
You did great. You know that, right?
宝宝快到妈妈这儿来
Come here, baby.
这没什么大不了的  我们会没事的
It's all right. We're okay. Yeah.
我想着重强调这一段
I'll take the stress very literally here.
就顺便提一句  你觉得呢
Just one quick-- you think?
还有接下来这个部分  麻烦用粗体标明
And on this next part, would you make sure you bold that?
克里斯  帮我把这个输入到提词器里去
Oh, Chris, I need you to load this in the teleprompter for me.
斯蒂夫·施密特说你不用发表演说
Steve Schmidt told me you weren't making a speech.
不  我要发表演说
No. I am making a speech.
斯库里已经跟里克·戴维斯说好了
Scully cleared it with Rick Davis.
快点帮我输入到提词器里去  好吗
So just go ahead and load it, okay?
好的
Okay.
好的  记得着重强调这一点
Okay, so, on the stress on this one, I'll take it.
-天哪  -抱歉
- Jesus! - Hey, sorry.
斯蒂夫  我现在有点混乱
Steve, I'm getting a bunch of mixed messages here.
州长她到底要不要做败选演讲呢
Is the Governor giving a concession speech or not--
我已经说过五遍了
I've already said this five times already.
她不需要做演讲
She is not giving a speech.
她好像并不这么认为
Well, she seems to think otherwise.
轮不到她说话
Well, she's not.
那你希望我怎么跟她说呢
What do you want me to tell her?
就跟她说她用不着上台演讲
Tell her she's not fucking speaking!
可是你们俩都挺有决心的...
Okay, well, you both seem pretty certain--
我的决心大于她的决心
well, let my certainty supersede her certainty.
该死的
God damn it!
斯蒂夫
Steve.
你要见我吗
You want to see me?
是的  这边请
Yes. This way.
抱歉
Excuse us a moment.
我听说你准备发表演说
I understand you've prepared a speech. Is that correct?
是的  我想对约翰为这个国家
Yes, I have. I want to salute John
所做的一切致以敬意
for everything he's done for this country.
不行  你不能上台做演讲
It's not going to happen. You're not giving a speech.
为什么呢  斯蒂夫
And why is that, Steve?
你不能上台演讲
You're not giving a speech
因为副总统的候选人从未
because the vice presidential candidate
在选举日当晚做败选演讲
has never given a concession speech on election night.
选举结束不是关于你
It's not about you.
而是关于整个国家
It's about the country.
可是凡事总有第一次
Yeah, well, there's a lot of things never been done before.
州长同志
Governor...
就在今天  美国选出了
This country has just elected the first
历史上第一位黑人总统
African- American president in the history of its existence.
这场败选演讲
And it is the concession speech
将正式承认结果的合法性
that will legitimize his succession as commander in chief.
这场演讲异常庄重严肃
It is a serious and solemn occasion,
约翰·麦凯恩  只有约翰·麦凯恩
and John McCain, and only John McCain,
才有资格发表这个演讲
will be giving this sacred speech.
自美利坚合众国成立的那一刻起
This is how it has been done in every presidential election
总统竞选的规则就是如此
in every presidential election since the dawn of the Republic,
而你  萨拉·佩林
and you, Sarah Palin,
你对于这一伟大的美国传统
will not change the importance
只能遵守  不能改变
of this proud American tradition.
"我们已经尽了全力去战斗"
"We fought-- we fought as hard as we could."
"虽然最终结果令我们矮人一头"
"And though we feel short,"
"但这只是我的失败"
"The fail-- the failure is mine."
老天  别这么说...
Oh, jeez, no--
马克  我并没觉得我矮啊
I don't feel that short, Mark.
"深感惭愧"  老大
"Fell short," Boss.
是啊  真是多谢了
Yeah, thanks.
"深感惭愧"  打错了
"Fell short." It's a typo.
-约翰  -萨拉
- John. - Hi, Sarah.
我们虽败犹荣
Well, we fought the good fight.
没错
Mm-hmm, we did.
现在让我去好好感谢一下我们的国家吧
Now I'm just gonna get out there and thank America.
我已经等不及要对你献上我崇高的敬意了
I can't wait to get out there and thank you.
我为你写了一份发自肺腑的颂词
I have a speech written that is a real tribute to ya.
不用了  我想他们已经安排好了
No, I think these guys have that covered.
对吗  斯蒂夫
Right, Steve?
是的  我们已经搞定了
Yes, sir. We have it covered.
我只是想让大家都看看你是一个多棒的人
I just wanted people to know what a great man you are.
谢谢你
I appreciate that,
但是他们已经安排好了
but these guys got it all worked out.
我们该走了  先生
Yeah, you know, we probably should get going now, sir, so...
好的
All right. Good.
那我们过会儿见了
Okay. We'll see you afterwards.
期待你精彩的演讲
I'll see you out there.
你现在已经是共和党的领袖了  萨拉
You're one of the leaders of the party now, Sarah.
你不能被像林博这样的极端分子打倒
Don't get co-opted by Limbaugh and the other extremists.
一旦你退让  他们将会毁掉整个政党
They'll destroy the party if you let them.
别忘了  你是个冰球妈妈
Remember, you're a hockey mom.
你只不过是想做出一些改变
You just wanted to make a difference,
而你的确做到了
and you did.
你为我们带来了一场巨大的变革
A big, huge difference.
为此我将永远心怀感激  谢谢你
I'll always be grateful. Thank you.
-该走了  先生  -谢谢你  约翰
- We should go, sir. - Thank you, John.
我亲爱的朋友们  我们...
My friends, we have--
我们已经携手走到了这段征程的尽头
we have come to the end of a long journey.
美国人民发出了自己的声音
The American people have spoken,
这声音是如此的清晰响亮
and they have spoken clearly.
就在刚才  很荣幸
A little while ago, I had the honor
我给巴拉克·奥巴马参议员打了个电话
of calling Senator Barack Obama...
向他...
to congrat--
别这样
please.
向他当选为我们彼此都深爱的美国的
To congratulate him on being elected
下一任总统而表示祝贺
the next president of the country we both love.
不管我们之前有什么分歧
Whatever our differences,
我们都同为美国人
we are fellow Americans.
您说的对
Yes, sir!
你们对我的支持  你们为我所做的一切
I am so deeply grateful to all of you
我将永远铭记在心  并心怀感激
for the great honor of your support and all you have done for me.
当然
I am also, of course,
我还想对萨拉·佩林州长表示由衷的感谢
very thankful to Governor Sarah Palin,
她是我见过的最好的竞选人之一
one of the best campaigners I have ever seen.
你还是认为她能胜任吗
Still think she's fit for office?
谁在乎呢
Eh, who cares?
48个小时之后  没有人会记得她是谁
In 48 hours, no one will even remember who she is.
我们期待她在阿拉斯加州能大展拳脚
We can all look forward with great interest
也期待她能为共和党  为整个国家
to her future service to Alaska,
做出更大的贡献
the Republican party and our country.
萨拉  萨拉  萨拉
Sarah! Sarah! Sarah!
她确实犯过不少错误
There were numerous instances of her saying things
这些错误不仅会让人质疑她的诚信
that were not accurate that opened the door to criticism
也将授予那些批评她的人以话柄
that she was being untruthful and inaccurate.
我认为她现在仍然在继续这种错误
And I think that is something that continues to this day.
你认为那些批评都是公正的吗
And you think that's fair criticism?
是  我认为那些批评是公正的
I think that's fair criticism.
可是早前你就说过她什么都不懂
Early on, though, you apparently said she doesn't know anything.
在她参选之后
In the immediate aftermath of her selection,
我们很快就发现...
it was clear to us that we...
发现我们有很多工作要做
had a lot of work to do.
对你而言  选择萨拉·佩林是考虑赢得选举
For you, picking Sarah Palin was about winning an election,
而不是考虑
not necessarily about
副总统的最佳人选
who's gonna be best as vice president.
我的职责是提出政治建议
My job is to give political advice.
为了赢得选举
We needed to do something bold
需要兵行险招
to try to win the race.
如果能重新来过
If you had it to do over again,
你还会挑选她作为竞选搭档吗
would you have her on the ticket?
世上没有后悔药  安德森
You don't get to go back in time, Anderson,
人生没有重来的机会
and-- and have do-overs in life.
*天佑美利坚*
? God bless America again ?
*主啊  当你看见她深陷困苦*
? You see all the trouble that she's in ?
*请拂去她脸上的尘土*
? Wash her pretty face ?
*拭去她眼中的泪水*
? Dry her eyes and then ?
*主啊  请永远庇佑美利坚*
? God bless America again ?
*天佑美利坚*
*当你看见她深陷困苦*
? You see all the trouble that she's in ?
*请拂去她脸上的尘土*
? Wash her pretty face ?
*拭去她眼中的泪水*
? Dry her eyes and then ?
*天佑美利坚*
? God bless America again ?
*请拂去她脸上的尘土*
? Wash her pretty face ?
*拭去她眼中的泪水*
? Dry her eyes and then ?
*主啊  请永远庇佑美利坚*
? God bless America again. ?